PAUL: Yes, the last class was optional, it was just for installation issues on Wednesday, okay? So, nothing with respect to teaching. It was just only resolving the doubt, so don't get confused.
PAUL: Perfect.
PAUL: So, today we'll be continuing the session, okay? So, like, last time as we were discussing, and this time I have kept the code in GitHub also, so you will be getting the GitHub links.
PAUL: in your Notion?
PAUL: Just wait 1 minute.
PAUL: Okay, fine, if this is your first class, not to worry, okay? And last class, as we were facing that, how many of you got that kernel crash issue? Please let me know in the chat, in the last class.
PAUL: kernel crash issue, okay?
PAUL: Okay, and anyone solved it?
PAUL: Very specifically.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Had it, solve it. Great. Few people have solved it, and few people have not.
PAUL: Alright, so let's start today's session. Okay, I will start sharing my screen. Okay, and here you will be seeing the GitHub link.
PAUL: Okay, I hope, everybody is able to get the GitHub link, okay?
PAUL: So, it's available in Notion. Okay, and just wait, I think people are telling it's their first class, so I'll be sharing the link to the Notion in the chat.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: I've shared it.
PAUL: No, This is the repo, okay, that we'll be using. Few things I have updated.
PAUL: Okay, and
PAUL: Majorly, all the notebooks and other stuff, so everything that I have very specifically mentioned here. Okay, so today we'll be going through the same stuff, okay? So, like, last class, we have already done, 01 introduction.
PAUL: Okay, so introduction and fundamentals notebook, and then we were going through this particular notebook, the simple rag lanching.
PAUL: Okay, so this particular notebook that we'll be doing, today. Okay, so let's… Let me open…
PAUL: And T protein…
PAUL: Okay, what you guys can do, simply see, like,
PAUL: you guys take a clone of the latest one that I have shared, very specifically.
PAUL: I think, that should be fine. Okay, I have no issues. Okay, take a… I think it will be better if you take a clone of the current repo.
PAUL: Current repo clone. I think everybody knows how to do a cloning operation.
PAUL: Alright, so… it's pretty much simple, like, if this is…
PAUL: For example, you have to take this link that I have shared.
PAUL: And if you are working with VA's code, Bessel.
PAUL: Visual Studio Code, for example.
PAUL: Okay, just wait.
PAUL: So, like, you will be getting this particular source control option from there. You can click on this clone repo option.
PAUL: Okay, and you will be getting this, provide the URL. So, simply you need to pass the URL and hit enter that.
PAUL: The other way is simply, like, if you don't want to clone, you can download it also. You can say download zip. So, both the ways works, whichever way works for you. Because few things I have updated, so I want you guys to be…
PAUL: On the same track with me.
PAUL: Okay, it's just, solving the FIS issue, that kernel crash, few things that I got.
PAUL: The repo link is available in Notion, okay? Please check.
PAUL: the notebook, I think everybody can get it. Here you can see, 22nd November, Exploring LandChain, and here you have the GitHub link.
PAUL: Yes, if you have already downloaded, then also you can do a cloning operation.
PAUL: Alright, Salman, Fire's installation was solved by installing Quanta. Okay, fine.
PAUL: So, once you guys are ready, like, cloning, whatever operation you have done, okay, so cloning you have done, or probably downloading you have done.
PAUL: Okay, so the next step is basically to open that folder in,
PAUL: VS Code. As simple as that.
PAUL: And, one thing, so how many of you, like, want me to create a new notebook and execute cell by cell?
PAUL: Okay, like, cell-by-cell execution I also do, but, like, very specifically write it, okay?
PAUL: Because that will take more time, probably. You will have lesser amount of time to discuss the doubts, but fine.
PAUL: Because I think that's why I added so much print statements.
PAUL: If you are guys not comfortable with brain segment, fine, okay? Today, because then the space will be pretty much slow.
PAUL: I will do a copy-paste of the cells in a new notebook.
PAUL: Please check Notion for GitHub links.
PAUL: Okay, it is available in Notion, please have it checked.
PAUL: Okay, once you guys are ready, please let me know. I'm sharing the link to the Notion once more.
PAUL: It's not getting pasted, just… People, please join on time. If people are joining later, I can see.
PAUL: How to make a clone in new window? Just click on the version control. So, for example, you have open VS Code, okay, you have to click on this button, the source control, and there you will be getting the clone ripple. And then, basically, the link that you will be getting from GitHub. Please do that.
PAUL: Yes, if you want, you can create a virtual environment again.
PAUL: And, this time, like, very specifically, the changes that I have done, if you look into requirement.txt, okay, quickly, I'll be showing the requirement.txt. It's pretty much the same stuff.
PAUL: Like, for Fire CPU, we can use a little version also, I've actually fixed that issue. I was testing out with different versions of Fires.
PAUL: Like, I was getting the same problem, but at the end of the day, it was a C++ issue. Okay, so I resolved it. It was only about a simple import statement that we'll be talking about. So, like, you can use your previous environment also, I have no issues in that.
PAUL: And very specifically, okay, like, as we are working with Langchain 1.2+, okay, so I have created this input reference. So whenever I look into the forum.
PAUL: Okay, so where people are asking, doubts, okay, so where they are always using wrong inputs. So that's why I have created this particular, document.
PAUL: So, the main things that you'll be using, and very specifically, what are the imports. So, that's why, which is the correct version and the depicated version. So, later on, after this lecture, that you guys can actually go through this.
PAUL: Okay, so let me know once you guys are ready, then actually I will start executing.
PAUL: everything is updated in GitHub, okay? So follow GitHub, whatever the stuff is. GitHub. That's why I asked you guys to take a clone, as simple as that.
PAUL: Let me just open Lubensaf in the meantime.
PAUL: Alright guys, please let me know once you guys are ready.
PAUL: Okay, so a quick, go-through that will be going.
PAUL: Okay, and then, so let me, I will just create a new notebook for now. Okay, and this new notebook, like, you guys don't need to create it, it's only that I'll be taking a copy-paste from this existing code. The idea is to go slow, okay?
PAUL: Because as few people were telling. So, first of all, let me just create a notebook.
PAUL: boy, where it is coming, okay?
PAUL: You guys don't need to create this notebook.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: You guys can execute the same notebook.
PAUL: Okay? You guys don't need to change anything.
PAUL: Alright, so, the first part was all about the installation of the libraries, okay? So, here, very specifically in the last class, also, we have discussed so much about creating environments, activating environments, okay? So, I think by this time, you guys should be familiar with that part.
PAUL: So, as you can see, like, if you are working with UV, then always use uvpip install. If you are not working, if you are directly working with Python, please use only pip. If you are working with Conda, then use conda install.
PAUL: Now, in the next step, this was all about the check. So, in the last class, if you remember, like, a few people were telling, very specifically for land-chain AI, okay? So, there is no attribute, like, dot underscore underscore version, okay? Now, this is the part, so what I will do, I will just take a copy of this one.
PAUL: bet.
PAUL: So right now, I'm just doing a version check that all the major packages that we are working with is available or not.
PAUL: Okay? So, import sys, and very specifically, like, import, live and metadata version, this is used to check the version of a particular package, as Langchain OpenAI was failing in our last class.
PAUL: Because of, this particular attribute of underscore, underscore, version, underscore, underscore is not available for Clangchain OpenAI directly, okay? So, that's why,
PAUL: Now you'll be seeing that by using metadata, so most of the things are getting imported, okay? So please have a check on this one.
PAUL: I think the font is a little bit big.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: So, I think this part should be clear, because in the last class, we have done it.
PAUL: It's pretty much a simple check, just to check that majorly, like, all the versions are available or not.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: If you are creating new environment, please use that particular kernel. If you are using your previous environment, please use the previous kernel, okay? So there is no restriction in that. It's totally up to you.
PAUL: Alright, now, in the next step, after we have done a check, okay, the next thing is the most important part, which is basically the import section.
PAUL: Okay, so… It won't create a problem, don't worry.
PAUL: If I'm using the older version, there won't be any type of problems, I think.
PAUL: Alright, now, this particular, OS environment, which I have kept it, okay? Like, K, empty, duplicate, leave, okay. Now, this is, something new. In the last class, I have not added it, okay, and this is very specifically for files.
PAUL: Okay, so, like, in the simple rag language, and okay, because this is actually
PAUL: a C++ issue, okay, and I have kept this particular issue. So, because of fires, the kernel was getting crashed.
PAUL: Okay, and this is very specifically because of liboomt. Okay, in Mac, it's lib OMP that I am getting, so you guys also use that very specific, environment variable, KMP duplicate lib is equal to true. Okay, so that's why I've kept this. Whenever you are working with files.
PAUL: Because right now, we are working with Jupyter Notebooks, okay? So, in Jupyter Notebooks, multiple instances are created. I execute the same cell multiple times, so it becomes a problem. So very specifically, what I have done, I have added it.
PAUL: Into this import section, import tools. This is very specifically for files only, so that the kernel doesn't get crashed.
PAUL: Now, in the next step, so setting up our path, like anything that I want to call, through my absolute path or relative path.
PAUL: Then comes importing my, variable, which is basically the, .env file. For that, I am using this package.env.
PAUL: Okay, then, few, other, I can say packages are there. One is the Langchen Community, then you have the Langchen Text Splitter, then Langshan OpenAI. So you guys can work with Gemini also, and today I'll be showing you, like, how to work with offline LLMs.
PAUL: and offline embedding models, that part also. Okay, so this is very specific to OpenAI, and I think everybody should be familiar by now how to work with Gemini.
PAUL: Yes, please let me know. If you are working with Gemini.
PAUL: This import needs to be changed.
PAUL: Yes, I think everybody has done it in the last class.
PAUL: Okay, Sunil, if you want to use AWS Bedrock, just check the documentation.
PAUL: Alright, now,
PAUL: Very specifically, I'm using Fires, as you can see here. Okay, so this is a, open-source vector store.
PAUL: And a few Langchen Core components that I'm using, very specifically for creating the template, then for creating chains, I am using runnable pass-through, and finally our string output parser, okay, which will throw the output of the LLM as a string.
PAUL: Okay, so these are the next, I can say, major imports that we do have.
PAUL: So, what I will do, so let me just execute this particular cell.
PAUL: Okay, so all the imports are successful and compatible with Langchain 1.0.
PAUL: Yes, OpenAI is not free, you need to purchase the credits. I think initially you will get some free credits that you can work through.
PAUL: Now, in the next step, so this is the part where, very specifically, Okay.
PAUL: So, as I am working with OpenAI, okay, so I have kept this particular check. Okay, now, if you guys are working with some other… okay, so for example, if you go into your .env.example, okay, so Google API key.
PAUL: So, this is the other one that you had.
PAUL: So, what you can do… so, by default, if I run this right now, you will see that it will show you your OpenAI API key.
PAUL: Okay, so similarly, if you want to have a check, just update this for Gemini, if you guys are working with Gemini. Okay, so the Google API key.
PAUL: Okay, and you will see that, very specifically, the Google API key that we had, it will be loaded. So right now, in this project, I think I have my .env file, Google API key, but it's telling that
PAUL: Okay… Google API case successfully loaded.
PAUL: Okay, actually, this one I have not updated yet.
PAUL: Because of data discommunities.
PAUL: Okay, and you will see that the current Google, I can see it's just about the variable. I think everybody understands this one, that you guys just need to update the variable, and nothing more.
PAUL: Now, in the next step, once this part is done, now in the next step.
PAUL: We will be setting up our document loading part.
PAUL: So, for document loading, very specifically, we'll be using a PDF. I have already provided you the tension.pdf in the last class also. If you're working with smaller PDFs, please change the name of that particular PDF.
PAUL: As simple as that. Okay, it's fine that you might work with smaller PDFs, okay, it's totally fine, but just update that particular document here. So right now, in the first step, I have just passed a path, and this is a relative path. This is not an absolute path. Relative path will work fine.
PAUL: Now, in the next step, so once we have done the relative path, definition, okay, now this is just a check if the file exists or not. Okay, this is simple Python, there is nothing AI which is going on. If the file exists, then only we are using this PyPDFloader.
PAUL: package to read our PDF file. So, right now, if I ask you, using which package we are, loading, or basically reading or parsing the PDF file, it is using the pipe PDF.
PAUL: So, very specifically, in your requirement.txt, if you go, so here, somewhere, you will be seeing there is a PI PDF, okay? This PDF processing, package. So, this package is responsible. Now, later on, when we'll be talking about data parsing, I'll be talking about multiple other ways of parsing.
PAUL: But for now, this is the most basic way of reading periods.
PAUL: Okay, so once…
PAUL: Okay, so right now, in the next step, so the object, so using the object, I am just, loading the document, and right now, everything will be saved inside this particular documents variable.
PAUL: Okay, and right now, the length of the document, the total number of pages, okay, so a lot of print statements that I've given, so that it becomes easier for you to, understand exactly what is there within the document.
PAUL: The length of the document, then comes the… we are printing out the first 500 characters, we are looking into the metadata, okay, and the total character across all pages.
PAUL: Okay, so in the next step, so right now, as you can see, loaded 15 pages from attention.pdf.
PAUL: No, right now it won't understand table format and other stuff.
PAUL: Okay, so the first thing it's printing, okay, loaded 15 pages.
PAUL: Then comes the first, 500 characters that you have.
PAUL: Okay, then, printing out the metadata, and the total number of characters across all pages, which is close to, right now, 40,000.
PAUL: Okay, I think this is pretty much standard, guys. Please let me know.
PAUL: In the last class, we have already executed this part.
PAUL: Please use simple rack chain. I have just created, this is for test. You guys…
PAUL: I'm creating and writing this code, so you guys just need to execute simple rack launch, and don't be confused.
PAUL: Alright guys, please let me know, can I proceed ahead with the next part? As you know that we have loaded the document, so after loading the document, what is the next step?
PAUL: Yes?
PAUL: Junking.
PAUL: I think everybody remembers we need a text splitter, so for that, we have the package of Langchen text splitters. So once we have done the chunking… okay, so for now, we'll be using the basic chunking mechanism, okay, which is the recursive text splitter.
PAUL: In the last class, I told you, like, more than 70% of the times, okay, or even 80% of the times, so this is the text reader that you will be working with.
PAUL: So, right now, this is the recursive character text splitter, okay? Now, this character text splitter follows multiple types of rules, like,
PAUL: very specifically, how to do the splitting mechanism. So, for that, first, I mentioned, okay, the chunk size that you have to maintain is 1024, okay? Then comes the chunk overlap, which is 128, and these are all in characters, guys, okay?
PAUL: Then, in the next step, the length function, the length of the chunks later on, if you want to find it.
PAUL: And then, finally, you have the separators. Now, these are the actual rules that we have defined to do the splitting mechanism.
PAUL: So, the priority is always given to double slash n, which means a paragraph, okay? Then comes slash end, new line, okay? And then you can see simple splitting, like, space.
PAUL: Okay, and finally, if nothing is there, then character.
PAUL: Okay, so based on that, we have very specifically defined this particular mechanism.
PAUL: So right now, this is the most basic splitting one. Later on, when we dive into much more splitters, very specifically, we use a library, a separate library, to do the splitting mechanism.
PAUL: Okay, so we'll be talking about that much more in depth. There are close to 8 to 10 different splitting mechanisms, and it totally depends upon your data. So you have to analyze your data, and then you have to take a decision.
PAUL: that which particular splitter that you need to use. Okay, but remember, recursive characters text splitter works more than 70% of the times.
PAUL: Now, this particular, text underscore splitter, so we have defined, so this is basically the object that we have created for the recursive character splitter. Now, in the next step, what we'll be doing?
PAUL: So we will apply the splitting of the document. So, previously, if you remember, so everything was saved inside this document variable. Okay, now, we will use directly this particular document variable, and we will pass it inside our splitter.
PAUL: So, text splitter.splitDocuments, and the previous instance of our document that we are passing. And later on, we are referring it as chance.
PAUL: Okay, and then finally, displaying the split results, okay, so the length of the documents, okay, and the length of the chunks, what is the average chunk size that we are getting. So here, this is a sum operation. So, this is an average chunk size that you are getting, okay, based on the formula that we have written. So, this is basically a formula.
PAUL: As simple as that, okay. And then printing out a few of the chunks, okay, with the content information and the metadata.
PAUL: So, right now, you can see, split 15 documents into 49 chunks.
PAUL: Average chunk sizes goes to 873 characters.
PAUL: Okay, chunk 1 length 986, because the max value that we have passed here is 1024. It cannot surpass that.
PAUL: Okay, with that, the metadata information is also getting printed.
PAUL: And very specifically, we are just printing out the top 200 characters.
PAUL: Okay, not all the characters in the chunk.
PAUL: So right now, based on this, so I have just kept here the, 3 chunks. Okay, you can change this number 3 to, like, 4, 5, 6, the max number that you can pass is, like, 49. As you know that the… you can see then the total number of chunks.
PAUL: If you want to look into all the chunks, very specifically, like, page underscore content that you can directly use, okay?
PAUL: Now, once your chunks are ready.
PAUL: Okay, so what is a metadata? Metadata gives you the information about the PDF. So right now, if you look into, okay, who produced the PDF, who is the creator of the PDF, when the PDF was created, who was the author, keywords.
PAUL: So whenever you are creating a PDF, okay, by default, for example, if you have worked with Adobe PDF Reader, or any type of, like, PDF annotation tools or PDF editing tools, okay, so when you create a PDF and you try to save it, there is always an option of metadata.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: So, that particular metadata that we are loading up.
PAUL: Who provides the PDF metadata? The author of the PDF? Who is releasing?
PAUL: Alright, now in the next step…
PAUL: As we have done the chunking.
PAUL: So, after the chunk, what you need to do?
PAUL: We need to work with embeddings, okay? So, I think I need to work with Gemini, because I have loaded the Gemini environment variable, okay?
PAUL: You guys can work with OpenAI also. I think you guys are smart by now, and you guys will be able to use.
PAUL: open here, okay? Because if you look here, in this, simple reaction, I think, here I have
PAUL: Okay, so create embeddings, so here you can see the OpenAI embeddings, last time we have talked about this one, and below, this is the code that I have commented it, which is for Google Gemini embeddings, okay? So for now, I'm using the Gemini embeddings.
PAUL: But Gemini, I don't have a paid one, I think.
PAUL: So, right now, what I have done… so, very, very important, guys, please look and always remember the imports.
PAUL: Okay, so LanChen Google Gen AI. So, it means that you need to install the package, LanChen-google hyphen AI, okay? And the import is basically, with the underscore always.
PAUL: And here, I am selecting a model, the Gemini Embedding 001 model, so it's a very good model, I can say.
PAUL: Okay, and somehow better than OpenAI also, okay, according to benchmarks.
PAUL: And then, just to show you, okay, how an embedding looks like, okay, so this is a sample text that we have passed.
PAUL: Then in the next step,
PAUL: Once you have done the sample text, okay, so I think I need to call our sample embedding.
PAUL: Okay?
PAUL: sample embedding, once we have passed it. Okay, then… okay, so here, in the print statements, you can see, so right now, this will be… okay, so…
PAUL: Gemini embedding hyphen 001. Okay, few things with respect to the print statements I have not added, but I think you guys are smart enough to understand that.
PAUL: Alright, so based on the embedding model that I have used right now, okay, so the embedding that I mentioned that I… the default one that is getting picked up for me is 768. And if you remember very specifically, okay, now this…
PAUL: So here also you can pass something like a dimension.
PAUL: Okay, so dimensions… So here you can play with this particular parameter, I think 3072 is also available there.
PAUL: Okay, so… models, just wait to show me.
PAUL: Alright, so right now, the recent update, which is basically the latest one, I have directly picked up. Embedding 001, it, by default picks up 768, okay? And,
PAUL: Gemini embedding 001, so this is, like, the state of the art, so that's why, very specifically, I mentioned the dimension 30 to 72. But remember, this is a costlier operation. The idea is that you should always check with lower dimensions. That is the bare minimum requirement. So always look into the developers page of Gemini.
PAUL: embeddings.
PAUL: So, if I go here, and if I look into…
PAUL: batch embeddings below that. Okay, so these are the dimensions available. 768 also you can pass. Okay, or 1536, I think that should also work.
PAUL: Okay, so if I change this to 1536.
PAUL: Okay, so right now, if I go here…
PAUL: Okay, the default one is getting picked up with… Just wait.
PAUL: What is the use of dimensions? So, generally, whenever you are creating any vector, you have to define that the numeric representation that you want to create it for a text, okay? So, what will be the size of that?
PAUL: So, one thing, okay, because very specifically, I have passed here the dimension is 15… 136.
PAUL: Okay, but here it is printing 3072.
PAUL: higher the dimensions, I can say that sometimes you get better results. Okay, so let me just show you. Okay, so now see, this is a dimension list, okay, and based on that, benchmark have been provided. Now, you can see that,
PAUL: 2048, this is one dimension. MRL stands for Matroshka Representative Learning, which is used very specifically for embeddings.
PAUL: Okay, so you can see here, like, 128 embeddings, the benchmark is low. Then, if you're increasing the size, it's getting better. If you're increasing more, somehow better. Then again, 768, I can say yes, somehow better.
PAUL: Then 1536, this is…
PAUL: More better, I can say. Then we increased more, but we can see here right now, it has dropped by 0.01. Okay, so the idea is that whenever you are working with dimensions.
PAUL: So, like, I feel that 1536 is always a good number, so these two are my favorites. I don't, always…
PAUL: Prefer working with higher dimensions when I'm working with paid embedding models.
PAUL: Okay, for open source embedding models, I can go with higher numbers, like 30764032, okay?
PAUL: So, whenever you are telling that, I want 768 dimension, it means that when you are converting a simple piece of text, that piece of text will be getting converted into 768 floating numbers.
PAUL: As simple as that. Now, when you mention the dimension as 1536, okay, that piece of text will be converted into 1536 floating numbers.
PAUL: So, it is not necessary that if you are having higher dimensions, you will always get better results. Because right now, if you look into this particular benchmark, okay, so very less change. So, I really, like, I won't prefer always using or going with higher dimensions.
PAUL: No, okay.
PAUL: I hope everybody got the idea of dimensions.
PAUL: Okay, so now, this piece of code that we were working with, okay?
PAUL: Gemini embedding 001, and very specifically the dimensions I have mentioned here, 1536. Neither it is throwing an error.
PAUL: Okay, neither, it's throwing.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: If Gemini is giving you error, use OpenAI or something like that, okay. Later on, I'll be showing you working with,
PAUL: Langchain Google Generative.
PAUL: AI?
PAUL: embeddings. So right now, I'm just looking into the official documentation, which is provided by Langshan, because why the thing is not getting updated?
PAUL: So, right now, if you guys look into the documentation, okay, So, yes…
PAUL: So this is the same stuff that we have done, embed query.
PAUL: Okay, task type…
PAUL: Let me just look into the API reference ones.
PAUL: Because the idea is that, it should reflect the same…
PAUL: Dimension. And we totally have that particular control.
PAUL: Google Gemini…
PAUL: Okay, where is the embedding part?
PAUL: Okay, so this is the actual documentation, so some things might be deprecated.
PAUL: So, very specifically, Google Generative Known. This is not the class, our class is the embedding class.
PAUL: Just tweet.
PAUL: Because the idea is that later on, you guys should able to look into
PAUL: the documentation and solve your issues. So, very specifically, I am showing you that part.
PAUL: Because I feel, the line interference with Google's generative AI embeddings latest here.
PAUL: Google API key, embedded. Okay, now if you look into the params, Google API key is fine.
PAUL: Embed document… Embed document is fine, embed query is fine.
PAUL: But that particular,
PAUL: Upload with…
PAUL: Google Gen AI.embittings…
PAUL: This is the actual class. Okay, so within this class, I am looking into the source code.
PAUL: Just to check, because I feel that somewhere, dimensions has to be there.
PAUL: Okay, so yes, embed documents.
PAUL: output dimensionality is here. If you look into this one.
PAUL: Okay, so output underscore dimensionality is there. Okay, so let's try to use this and see that if it works or not.
PAUL: directly I am doing a change, because the idea was that if you change this, probably, to 768, the default size of, this one… okay, and if you see it till now, it's 30712, right?
PAUL: Embed query sample text.
PAUL: Okay, so let me just pass this one.
PAUL: And… for now…
PAUL: Okay, so you can see right now the dimensionality got changed. Okay, so that's why I always refer to the documentation. At any point of time, if you feel that, okay, so that's the fastest way of doing changes.
PAUL: Alright guys, I hope that… It worked, and… yes?
PAUL: Mortalza?
PAUL: It doesn't work right… Just check, guys.
PAUL: Please check, guys. Right now, I have done it.
PAUL: See, because I just referred to the documentation, okay, because even, like, I have not… most of the time, it totally depends upon this one, so let me see. Yes, 1536. Yes, it is getting updated, please check.
PAUL: Please look into this sample rag line. This is the current coding that I'm doing live in the class. For that, I'm just using this file. You guys need to refer to simple rag line chain notebook.
PAUL: Muttasar Hakim, fine, this is your fifth unanswered query.
PAUL: Right now, I'm executing the code, so I'm not looking into the chat.
PAUL: Please let me know. Do you want me to paste this line?
PAUL: And now, see, these things don't apply for OpenAI. This is very specific to Gemini. Just remember that.
PAUL: Now, later on, you might say why it is not working for OpenAI. OpenAI have a very specific dimension.
PAUL: And probably there are models which doesn't support different type of sizes. It's Google, Gemini embedding model which supports that. Okay.
PAUL: So, don't get confused.
PAUL: Yes, guys, please let me know, can I proceed ahead? Because this part…
PAUL: Yes, working with the dimensions, pretty much standard. Alright. Now, once we have defined our embeddings and the next step.
PAUL: we will be creating the, files, okay? So, if you are working with files, just be sure that,
PAUL: Import waste… okay. Now, Justin, this part, I think import ways… yeah. This, you guys have done, okay? Now, this is very specific for my Mac, I think it should work for Windows also. Okay, this part is important, otherwise your kernel might crash.
PAUL: Okay? So, just be sure previously you have done the input.
PAUL: That's the bare minimum requirement.
PAUL: Alright, so what we are doing, so right now, as you can see, the chunks that we have very specifically, so the length of the total chunks, okay, and this might take a time, so it totally depends upon your vector database. It depends on the
PAUL: different vector database. I cannot say that every vector database has the same speed of, like, uploading the embeddings and other stuff. It takes time. And right now, this is an open source one, so somehow I feel that this is slow as compared to other paid products in the market.
PAUL: And, very specifically, you can see for our vector store, I'm calling files from document, and then I am passing two things. The chunks and the embeddings. Two things I am passing, the actual content with the embeddings.
PAUL: Now, in the next step, as you can see, the virus vector store will be created, and then finally, all those chunks that we have created, it will be indexed to Virus VectorDB.
PAUL: Okay? And very specifically, we have given a path, so let me see that do I have an existing path or not, then I will delete it.
PAUL: Okay, so let me just delete. Previously, I have executed, so…
PAUL: Okay? So, yes. Now you will see that it will be created here. So, this is the local index. Okay, it means that in… within this folder, I am saving the information, okay, which will be basically a pickle file.
PAUL: Now, so vector store.save, so this is, I'm saving my VectorDB in my local machine, and this is the path that I have defined.
PAUL: Okay, so let me just execute now.
PAUL: creating files index from 49 chunks, you can see that this particular folder will be created in your local machine, which is the fires underscore index, the name of the folder that I have passed, and right now, all those 49
PAUL: I can say, chunks. Okay, all those embeddings are right now shaped.
PAUL: So this is the part where you created a vector database. Within that vector database, you did… so right now, this operation in most of the vector database, it can be referred to as an upload or an upset.
PAUL: Okay? So this is pretty much an… or in simple terms, an indexing operation.
PAUL: Okay, so this is the fast part. So, right now I have done it.
PAUL: Now, in the next step, my vector TB is ready. So, what I need?
PAUL: I need a retriever.
PAUL: Because at the end of the day, having a retriever, because I need to check that, yes, it's working or not.
PAUL: So…
PAUL: After creating the embeddings, we have uploaded the embeddings into a vector database in our local vector DB, which is the FIS one.
PAUL: Now, we will try to perform a retrieval operation, okay? And right now, in this particular retriever, okay, if you look into, so vector store as a retriever, okay, it means that within the vector store, I want to perform a retrieve operation. The type of operation will be a similarity score find.
PAUL: Okay, so which is basically the cosine similarity that is available, within our files. Like, every vector DB supports cosine similarity. Okay, there is no vector DB in the market which doesn't support cosine similarity.
PAUL: And right now, we want the top 4 most relevant chunks.
PAUL: Okay? Then we have few print statements, a retriever configured successfully, search type, the number of documents that we want to retrieve, which is 4. Very specifically, I am telling here, 4.
PAUL: Now, I will be passing a test query.
PAUL: So, what is the main topic of this document? So, this is a random question that I am asking. So, this is basically the query that I have.
PAUL: And then retriever.invoke.
PAUL: Okay? So, retriever.invoke, so I will invoke our initialized retriever. So here, I have done the initialization. In the latest step, I am just invoking it, and from there, I'll be getting the result.
PAUL: Okay? So, right now, let me just execute this. I'll think that I'll be getting some result.
PAUL: Okay, so right now, as you can see here, Document 1, similarly, you can click on the scroll, you can look into Document 1, Document 2, Document 3, and Document 4. So, these are the top 4, most, I can say, like, similar documents based on cosine similarity that we have defined.
PAUL: Is this part clear for everyone, what I am doing right now?
PAUL: And then, see, this part is just for printing out each retrip document. The top 4 documents that we had, the idea was to print out the document, content, and the metadata. So, basically, for that, that we have done.
PAUL: And actually, two information is there, page content and metadata. So this is just a simple for loop. I think everybody understands this one.
PAUL: Yes, there are other types of similarity also, like Euclidean distances there, Jacquardian metrics as there, so many others out there.
PAUL: The most basic one is the cosine similarity.
PAUL: Yes, guys, please let me know. Is this part executed? Because I think, in the last class, this is the part where the kernel cla- I think, crash was taking place.
PAUL: Right now, I'm not talking about re-ranking and other stuff, so please don't ask irrelevant questions.
PAUL: In which step we calculated the vector to text.
PAUL: Converted the text to vector, so this was basically the step that we have defined.
PAUL: this when you are taking… you are taking the chance, and you are doing the embedding operation.
PAUL: This is the step, guys. Because I am using this,
PAUL: I can say object of the Google Generative AIM. So this object that directly I passed it here. So I'm passing the chunk also. So this is the step where we have done the conversion of the text to vectors.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Alright, I will just complete this notebook, okay, and then probably, like, few questions that I can take it.
PAUL: Alright, now, because, this is the part which we have done, okay? Now, right here, you can see that I have not passed any LLM and other stuff.
PAUL: Okay? It's pretty much simple retrieval mechanism.
PAUL: And nothing more.
PAUL: Yeah, somebody's asking, is it mandatory to overlap the chance? Yes, the idea is for context, retention, okay, or preservation. That's why, yes, it is required.
PAUL: Now, let's talk about our LLM definition. So, very specifically, I think, in the last, class.
PAUL: We were… because right now.
PAUL: Okay, you can use an LLM which is OpenAI, or you can use an LLM which is
PAUL: Gemini, okay? So I think Gemini code I have in Notion, just wait.
PAUL: Somewhere here, it will be there.
PAUL: I think this is the one. Okay, great.
PAUL: because the Gemini code is there in the simple rag glanching, there I have not used it.
PAUL: Okay, so right now, so this is basically the input. Okay, always remember the import for…
PAUL: talking to an LLM, which is… it always starts with chat. Like, chat, OpenAI. Chat, Google Generative AI. Okay, so from the same package, if you look into the package, it's exactly the same. I'm using everything from the Google Suite, the LLM, as well as the embedding model.
PAUL: So, right here. So, it's not necessary to use the same, I can say LLM, you can always change the LLM. There is no restriction in that.
PAUL: Okay, so let me see that, whether the LLM works or not right now.
PAUL: Okay, and right now you can see that, yes, it is working fine.
PAUL: Okay, and I am getting the response from the LLM.
PAUL: So, simply, now we know that this is the LLM that we have defined, and that later on, even we'll be using it, okay, for our full rack call, okay, that we'll be doing.
PAUL: So the LLM definition we have done, see, if you guys are working with OpenAI, okay, so the OpenAI code is available here, I think this is there. Okay, so this is the actual LLM call that you have.
PAUL: So, Chat OpenAI, then comes your model selection, whichever model you want to work, GPT-5 Nano, 3.5 Turbo, okay, so all those models, anyone that you can select.
PAUL: Okay, and right here, some other parameters also that I have kept it, it's only for the explanation of parameters, very specifically.
PAUL: But right now, in our class, I am using the free version, okay? So based on that, I've kept it simple. Only two things, model and temperature for now.
PAUL: Now, in the next step.
PAUL: Okay, because the LLM has been tested, and it looks like
PAUL: So, if you change the temperature here, okay, so probably with respect to the output, things will change, okay? So, just to show you…
PAUL: Okay, so this is the current output, Z.
PAUL: Okay, so if I change it, so let's make it 0.9…
PAUL: Okay? I hope everybody understands.
PAUL: Okay, so generally, like, we go with a zero, okay, which is pretty much for getting deterministic output. Otherwise, this is basically the creativity.
PAUL: Okay, like, if you change it based on that, the creativity of the LLM changes. As simple of that. Creativity, when I'm talking, it simply means the response of the LLM will change based on this particular temperature parameter.
PAUL: Okay? At the end of the day, the context is pretty much the same stuff, but if you look into the words and the other stuff has somehow changed.
PAUL: Okay, so this is what temperature does.
PAUL: Totally.
PAUL: Now, the LLM part we have worked with. Now, in the next step.
PAUL: The idea is to build our chain, okay? So, let me pass the LLM also with respect to the chain.
PAUL: In the last class, we have already discussed
PAUL: Okay, if you remember, so this is basically the retriever that we have. Okay, so…
PAUL: This is the retriever. Okay, it's the same piece of code, there is no change here, actually. I think, let me just delete this, okay? Otherwise, you guys might get confused.
PAUL: Okay, now the part is with respect to our final ranching build. So, to build our ranching, if you remember, I need, three things. The first is the retrieve docs.
PAUL: Okay, so the retrieve docs, which I refer as context.
PAUL: from, VDV, the vector DV,
PAUL: Then, the next step that you have is basically your query, the question that I'll be passing, and finally, that you have is your prompt. Okay, that will be defining. All these things will go to your LLM.
PAUL: So, this will be the call. So, your retrieve docs, Okay.
PAUL: Yes, dogs.
PAUL: So, your retrieve DOPs, plus query, plus prompt, and finally, all those information will go to the LLM to get your final response.
PAUL: So right here, so this is basically a system prompt that I have passed here, and inside this particular system prompt, pretty much generic, like, it can be much more complex. For now, the idea is to keep it simple. You are a helpful assistant for question-answering tasks.
PAUL: Use the following pieces of ritual context to answer the question. If you don't know the answer based on the context.
PAUL: Say that you don't know. So, directly, I'm telling, say that you don't know. Keep the answer concise and accurate, and finally, I am keeping this as placeholders, context and question, in this particular prompt template. Okay, now this is basically the prompt that I am passing.
PAUL: Okay? Now, this particular system prompt that I'll be passing within the Langchen class, the class is called as Chat Prompt Template, okay? And within this class, I am passing this particular piece of information. The idea is to pass this particular prompt to your final write sheet.
PAUL: So that's why, so this is the part with respect to the prompt that we have defined.
PAUL: Now, once we have done this, okay, now we'll be building our final rack chain. If you remember, we have talked about LCL in our last class. What does LCL does? So, for example, if you have 3 to 4 different components, okay, so those components, we can bind them.
PAUL: How we can do the binding? It can be components, it can be simple functions also.
PAUL: All those functions, we can bind it through, your runnable pass, okay? And later on, we can execute them, all the pipelines, in one shot, okay? So, a simple pipe operator. If you have not referred to the last class.
PAUL: please go through, I think it was in Introduction and Fundamentals. Okay, so here, I think, I've given the example of this also. Like, where you have these functions, then through runnable Lambda, you can, actually create, the…
PAUL: chain object, and later on you can call all those chain objects directly in one shot. Okay, so this we have discussed in the last class, so now I'll be using this particular feature directly here.
PAUL: So, that…
PAUL: part with respect to the prompt is done. Then comes helfer function to format documents. Okay, so right now,
PAUL: This function that I'll be using later on directly to call it
PAUL: Okay, and so right now, if you look into doc.pageContent form, the idea is, later on, I'll be looking into this. Now, it is always not necessary, but you can use it.
PAUL: Okay, I feel that, yes, the retrieve documents, will actually get in a better format. So, because of that, the context will be better at any point of time. So, because of that, we are doing… and what are those docs? The retrieve docs. So, right now, I'm just doing a format operation. So, return slash and slash and means
PAUL: Paragraph files. Paragraph files. It means that if you have 10 chunks, all those chunks will be joined into a single document. And how they will be the splitting, or how they will be done? Like, slash and slash. So because of that, we are doing this particular operation.
PAUL: And this particular, reaction that we have, which is the context, okay?
PAUL: That is coming from the retriever. Now, from the retriever, the next operation is the… this function, which is basically the format tops, then comes your push, and
PAUL: Okay, finally, that I'll be passing through. Now, runnable pass-through. Now, this is a very specific function from LANCHIN. Okay, using this, you can pass it within a chain, like any type of text or question that you want to ask.
PAUL: And finally, the prompt LLM, and at the end of the day, I am telling that I am looking for a string output, okay? So now, if I execute this…
PAUL: the, operation, I have defined it, okay? Now, I'll be calling the chain. Till now, I have not… this is the part where we have only defined the chain.
PAUL: Okay? Runnable pass-through. So, using this runnable pass-through, I'll be passing a text within this later on. Because right now, this is just a placeholder within the chain. Later on, I'll be making it.
PAUL: Because right now, I have not passed any query, guys. Later on, I'll be passing the query within this chain. So, directly, you cannot pass it within the chain. So because of that, I have used this runner-L pass-through. It helps you to pass anything within the chain.
PAUL: Now, I'll be finally calling the chain, okay? So, it's time to call the chain.
PAUL: Okay, so I don't think I need it more. So what I've done, so this is my query that I have passed. What is the main topic or the subject of this document? Okay, this is query one, as you can see.
PAUL: And now you can see the rag chain that we have defined here.
PAUL: rag underscore chain, okay? Now, here I have just defined it, and now I'm calling it rad underscore chain dot invoke, and I'm passing the query.
PAUL: Okay? And directly, so these are a few print statements, just to show you the answer. Okay, and finally, the retrieve tops, if you want to get that, context with the answer. Okay, so I will just execute this one.
PAUL: And now, the first part is the answer. You always remember, this is the part that is the answer coming, okay? So here, it's telling that the main topic of the document is attention mechanism in neural networks, specifically in its visualization and its role in handling linguistic dependencies.
PAUL: Okay, so this is coming. And these are all the retrieved text, which is the output of the retriever, those four documents.
PAUL: Okay, so document 1, 2, 3, 4. Okay, and this is the final answer that we were looking for.
PAUL: Okay, as you can see here, like, encoder, cell potential layer, so all those things that are coming from this.
PAUL: Yes, guys, please let me know that this part is getting executed or not. Okay, now I will just look into the chat, because I have not looked into the chat for the past 10 minutes.
PAUL: Anirodh Prasad is asking, please explain context retriever format to us again.
PAUL: What is there to explain? I've already done it.
PAUL: So, this is the part where I'll first call our retriever. Okay, then in the next step, the output of the retriever will be taken as an input to this particular function of format docs. And right now, I am using LCL. Please refer to the last class if you have not gone through that.
PAUL: Okay? VectorDB is not same as SQLDB.
PAUL: These things I have discussed through Ash in previous classes, please don't get…
PAUL: Okay, please have a look into those things. VectorTV is used for high-dimensional data.
PAUL: Please explain indexing. Indexing, we have done it in this step. Okay, so this is the part with respect to indexing operation, guys.
PAUL: Okay, and after indexing, so here, directly, we are taking the output of the retriever.
PAUL: So, you can see this retriever object that I am using. If you remember, see, this is the retriever object that we have, this retriever.
PAUL: That I'm calling it here.
PAUL: This is an LCL, it means that you can combine multiple functions. So, like,
PAUL: First, just think about Retriever gave you that output. That output becomes the input for this particular function, the format doc. So, similarly, if you have multiple functions, simply, like, one by one, you can use a pipeline, okay, and you can call it. This, I have discussed in the last class. Please go through that LCL part.
PAUL: Okay? And right now, this runnable pass-through is pretty much blank, because later on, I'll be passing the query. If you want to pass anything within a chain, you need to use runnable pass-through.
PAUL: And with that, I am adding my prompt LLM and string output parser. So these things we have already defined previously. Okay, and this part is, like, not compulsory always, but if you want to get the LLM output directly as a string, then you use it.
PAUL: Is this part clear? Exactly what I have done?
PAUL: How the retriever knows.
PAUL: What else is the question? Aruna is asking how the retriever knows which embedding
PAUL: Like, which embedding to use for a query before passing to VectorDB?
PAUL: How the retriever knows which embedding.
PAUL: There is a vector database, it will try to compare all the chance, basically. So, which one will be having the closest or the highest similarity score, they will be taken out.
PAUL: Where is the embedding done before the query? Okay, now that is done automatically. We don't do it. Okay, Langshan takes care of that.
PAUL: Embedding is the operation which is being done during indexing. Dakshot.
PAUL: Alright, so pretty much the stuff that I have done, okay, this was all about this notebook. Okay, if you want me… okay, so, like, this is the same notebook that I have done. Here, more statements and other stuff are there, okay, which will help you to understand things in a better way.
PAUL: Okay, so it's pretty much, so, test, because the next things and others, whatever is there, I'll be executing in this particular notebook. So you guys don't need the test, you can directly work with a simple rag lanching.
PAUL: I can see everybody's message, don't ask me, can you see my message? Again.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Alright, so it's 10.15. Now tell me, like, for how many of you, everything got executed successfully in the chat, just do a thumbs up.
PAUL: Okay, Motoza is asking, does the size of the chunk affect…
PAUL: The similarities? Yes, yes, it affects.
PAUL: Back.
PAUL: It's, see, like, if somebody is telling module not sound error, just be sure you have the module in your environment.
PAUL: The idea is simple.
PAUL: everything in the rag is abstracted. Yes, like, if you're working, later on, I'll be showing you, like, how to build everything from scratch. Okay, because the idea was to start easy, then I will be showing you entire thing in Python.
PAUL: It will be a very long notebook.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: But for now, everything, like, if you do it in haystack, it's much smaller. If you do it in Llama Index, similar, similar. Okay, Haystack makes your life much more easier.
PAUL: Alright, so this is the first part that we have done, okay? So, for now, let I, covering.
PAUL: Now, let me take some queries.
PAUL: I'm watching now, everything executed, alright.
PAUL: People who are getting SOC don't ask me about
PAUL: current quota exceeded, okay, API exhausted, those are the things that you need to take care of.
PAUL: Okay? Because API and other stuff that I will… because later on, I'll be talking about
PAUL: The part where I'll be using everything in local.
PAUL: Perfect. Now,
PAUL: the next step, because I feel that I need to discuss that solution. Like, I don't know, many of you might get resource exhaust quota and some paid issues.
PAUL: So now, I'll be talking about a very specific notebook, okay, which is the local rack, okay? So before discussing this, the idea is that you guys should have downloaded OLAMA in your local machine. OLAMA download.
PAUL: Okay, so as you can see here, Olama available for Windows, for whichever operating system that you are doing. Okay, please download it based on your operating system. Okay, so this particular link, I'll be adding it in…
PAUL: Notion. Okay, so… Llama, download.
PAUL: Based in your operating system, please do download.
PAUL: Because now I'll be working with everything offline. Offline embedding models, then comes offline, LLMs, and the same piece of code, just embedding model I will change, and LLM I will change. Only two things.
PAUL: Because many of you are getting that resource quota, I don't know, like, Gemini and OpenAI, neither is working. So for them, going forward, try to use local LLMs and local embedding models in this course.
PAUL: Just download Olama. Don't ask me how big it is.
PAUL: Okay, the last time I downloaded, I think it was around 700MB or 800MB.
PAUL: Moama, the RF is asking, how can we convert embedding back into text from Retriever? Why will you be doing that operation? Nobody does that. Muhammad.
PAUL: Everybody convert text into numbers. Nobody does numbers into text. Because at the end of the day, you always have the information of the text. That is saved.
PAUL: Okay, 1.1 GB for Windows, great. Please do a download, similarly for Mac. I think few people have already downloaded, because this is a standard thing that we have been doing for the past one year in other batches also.
PAUL: While retrieving from, in vector database, we always save the information about chunk also, more motherfly.
PAUL: So, vagatha, nothing I can do if it's huge and slow.
PAUL: If I download it, I think within maximum, I think, 5 to 10 minutes, it will be done.
PAUL: Because at the end of the day, you guys need to work with. I don't want…
PAUL: people writing in the chat, resource quota, and other stuff. So, that's why I'm feeling, let's complete this part. Going forward, if you don't have OpenAI, if you don't have Gemini, just use local.
PAUL: All top KHMs are useful. Response? Yes, Sharadh, correct.
PAUL: Yes, Shiba, you can use hugging Face models also.
PAUL: I have no issue.
PAUL: You can use that all mini… okay, all mini embedding model, like, whole world uses it, but I don't kept it. I feel that that is pretty much outdated, rather than I have kept stuff which are much more used in
PAUL: I can say, in production.
PAUL: Nobody uses it in production, all meaning that.
PAUL: Avijit was asking which is the most used framework.
PAUL: I can say Lambchan, Llama, these are widely used.
PAUL: In the industry, whatever the stuff is there in your syllabus, that is used. Otherwise, why we'll be discussing that?
PAUL: Can we scale Ulama? Yes, if you have a good system, you have to set up your own infrastructure, you can scale it up.
PAUL: Under economical contention is no.
PAUL: to host an LLM to make things up, okay, you need. And right now, Ulama can be run within a Docker, so at any point of time, if you're scaling up, you know that you have to launch multiple Docker instances. If anybody has worked with Farget, it's pretty much easy.
PAUL: Yes, I think people who have worked with Farget, they might need.
PAUL: 1 million hits per second, yes, sir. For scales, like, yes, 1 million hits per second it can handle, but you have to launch multiple instances of Doppler, because the system will be pretty much big. Within that, if you launch probably 10 to 20 instances.
PAUL: Okay, so yes, it will be a cost line for at the end of the day. It will be an auto-scaling mode. If it scales down, automatically those Docker instances will be killed. If you get more hints, it will be launched.
PAUL: Yes, it is possible to add custom metadata.
PAUL: whoever is asking, please check Notebook 1. At any point of time when you are creating a document, you can add your custom return.
PAUL: How do we decide which similarity algorithm to use?
PAUL: A little bit experiment. Most of the things are hyperparameter. Nobody tells me I have to do experiment. Cosine similarity works more than 60-70% of the times.
PAUL: Why 4 Rohit? You can use 5, 10, 15 Roeth, I have no issues with it.
PAUL: Alright, so if you have guys download Olama.
PAUL: Okay, so what I will do, just boot.
PAUL: Let me just open up… my terminal.
PAUL: Okay, so I'm using an old version of Olama, doesn't matter, it might be on a newer version. And somewhere you will be seeing that, there will be an OLAMA
PAUL: I can see, in your Windows or somewhere, wherever the running task is there. So, by default, when you start with Ullama, okay, so ULAMA list is the command. Okay, in my case, you can see multiple types of models. In your case, it will be blank. The idea is to download a model, okay?
PAUL: So, the first one is Olama. Okay, so, run.
PAUL: like, this is an LLM. So, how to do the selection? So, let's tell you how to do the selection of models here. So, if you want an embedding model, just click on this embedding button. Okay, embedding Gemma.
PAUL: this is a model that you can run. You can see it's 300 million parameters, so I know that, yes, it will work pretty good in your system. There won't be any problem.
PAUL: This is one of my favorite models, Nomic Embed Text. I use it in production. Okay, so really a great one to work with. Okay, MXBI Embed Large. This is a larger model, but again, a state-of-the-art. Again, can be used in production.
PAUL: Okay, now this is a lighter version, okay, at any point. Then BGME3, really a very good one.
PAUL: Okay, then all-mini LM, okay, so really, like, the basic at any point of time if you want to work with.
PAUL: Smoothlick, Arctic Embed, this is also a good one. Okay, so always look into the sizes, there are so many embedding models, okay? So right now, I will prefer, like, I already have Nomic, so when you click here.
PAUL: Okay, you will see this command. Click on the model, whichever model you want, like embedding Gemma. Okay, and you'll be getting this particular copy option. Copy that.
PAUL: And paste it here, in your machine.
PAUL: Okay? Simply. So right now, what will happen? The embedding Gemma model will be downloaded in your local machine, and you can use it. Similarly, if you want to work with Nomic.
PAUL: Okay, click on Nomic Embed Text.
PAUL: Copy this.
PAUL: Okay, and paste it here.
PAUL: So these two are already available in my case, so I will pick up something else for now.
PAUL: I need something light, not very heavy.
PAUL: Yeah, so… Let's go use this one for me.
PAUL: So, you will see something like this, okay? So pretty much, like, if anybody has worked with Docker, pretty much, like, it pulls the model through that.
PAUL: Like, behind the scenes, Olama uses Docker, always.
PAUL: Use the command pull.
PAUL: You can use run also, run by the first, pull it and run it. But, right now, for embedding models, I use always pull. For LLMs, I might use run. Okay? Now you can see that, yes, I do have
PAUL: So, the model that I was working with, you can see here right now, MXBI Embed Large.
PAUL: Okay, so this embedding model got in my local machine.
PAUL: So this is how you select, okay? So right now, the list is long, you guys can play with it, okay, so whichever one is there. I have told you the top 3 ones right now.
PAUL: Now, selecting L&Ms.
PAUL: Is basically the next part.
PAUL: So right now, see, whenever you are working with LLM, just be sure you have good RAM, okay? Don't pick any model which is very, very high.
PAUL: That's a bad practice, like, if you are working with GPT OSs, okay? So right now, if you look into, size is 14 GB.
PAUL: Okay, and 14GB is the 20 billion parameter. If you're working with GPT OSS 120 billion, this is 65GB. So don't pull an LLM which is of very high size.
PAUL: Okay, in your local machine, you should know what is your RAM. If you have a RAM of 128GB, please use GPT OSS 120 billion. I have no issues.
PAUL: Now, the idea is that you should always use something light. I prefer, like, Gemma models, they are pretty much light.
PAUL: Okay, when I go here, you can see, like, 3GB models. Okay, I know that it will work good in my system. I do have a RAM of 32GB, so 10% I can allocate it to the LLM very specifically.
PAUL: Alright. Then, if you want to check others, okay.
PAUL: Like, you can work with, Llama 3.2. Okay, so this is also a good one. I think it will be in GB. Llama 3.2, it's close to 2GB. This is another LLM that you can play with. Okay, so anyone that you can work, you can work with Llama… okay, or you can get Gemma…
PAUL: But…
PAUL: I will prefer, like, you can use Gemma. Okay, if you want. I already have Gemma 3 in my local machine. Okay, so the same stuff. Now, this is the part, this is the LLM. Guys, understand. Olama and Gemma 3. I already have Gemma 3 in my system, guys.
PAUL: Okay, JMR3, 1 billion.
PAUL: Now, I have the 1 billion more.
PAUL: There is also the 4 billion model and the 12 billion model.
PAUL: Okay, so please use 1 billion for now.
PAUL: The idea is you won't be getting good results, but the idea is that, yes, the execution, that… because the model having higher parameters, okay, for sure will give you better results.
PAUL: Cloud versions you can use. Right now, the idea was to show you the offline one.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Volama has the cloud version also.
PAUL: So, this model, or anyone, because in my system, I think, I have one or two models, like, DeepSeek R1, then, Gemma3, and Llama 3.2. These three are the local LLMs that I have.
PAUL: So, similarly, you can use an embedding model.
PAUL: At any point of time.
PAUL: Okay, and then local NLM. So, both the things are local, it means that nothing you are paying for.
PAUL: Okay, so… please let me know you have downloaded an LLM, and as well as you have downloaded an embedding model.
PAUL: Please let me know in the chat with a thumb.
PAUL: Deepsake is good. Deepsake R1 is good.
PAUL: Okay, 73.5% going, not done, not done. Please, guys, do it, okay?
PAUL: Please do it, I will wait. Fine, I will wait for 5 minutes.
PAUL: It's just two cells change that we have to do. Rest of the code will be pretty standard.
PAUL: Yes.
PAUL: Okay, fine, it's, 10.30, okay, let's go for a 10 minutes break, and then we'll be back.
PAUL: Okay, like, after that, okay, just be sure you have those local LLMs, and the local embedding model.
PAUL: The idea is one embedding model and one. You don't need to download multiple LLMs and multiple embedding models. For now, only one LLM and one. Later on, after the class, you can do testing with multiple LLMs and multiple embedding models.
PAUL: Alright, so I'll be back in 10. Please do complete your downloads, and then we will continue.
PAUL: Alright, like…
PAUL: How many of you are getting, Olama installation issues? Like, in… right now, then I have to take a volunteer for Windows?
PAUL: In Mac, it's pretty much straightforward. There is no such complexities, but for Windows.
PAUL: In Mac, there is issue with Mac. It's pretty much straightforward.
PAUL: Installation done, everything working fine.
PAUL: Okay, alright.
PAUL: like, for Windows, okay, one of you can raise your hand. I will take a volunteer. Please let me know in the chat that I have the idea that you should have good internet connection.
PAUL: Download speeds can differ.
PAUL: Let me know in the chat, okay, who has got a good internet connection, and then everything is working for you.
PAUL: Karen Rathor, I already showed it in the class. It is totally up to you which model you want. You can use Nomic Embed.
PAUL: Or you can use Llama, okay?
PAUL: everything working. Rahul Singh, you want to share, then please raise your hand, Rahul.
PAUL: If you have an 8GB RAM, nothing I can do. Okay, go with the cheapest one, the smallest model, that's the bare minimum.
PAUL: Alright, Rahul, I will add you to a panelist.
PAUL: Alright, just, I'll stop sharing my screen.
PAUL: Rahul, I have added you, panelist, okay? And Rahul, you can start sharing the screen.
PAUL: If you are getting storage issue, nothing I can do, but then this thing needs to be taken care by you. If you have lesser storage.
PAUL: Alright, Rob. Okay? So, right now, you have done the installation of Olama, okay? So, close this, close this prompt, okay? Close this one. Okay. Click the Windows button.
PAUL: Windows, huh? And search for Olama, I think you will be getting something, Olama.
PAUL: Search for Ulama, huh? Click on that Ulama app.
PAUL: Okay? Now, this is the part where you can chat with, models, okay? So, this is the default Ollama interface, okay? So, for example, you can type anything, just ask a simple query.
PAUL: Any random query for now.
PAUL: You should have selected which model you have downloaded that you should have selected 1 billion one year.
PAUL: Just do something, tell me what is 2 plus 2, something like that.
PAUL: Pretty much simple.
PAUL: Okay, so right now you can see that, yes, it is, throwing the response.
PAUL: Okay, so, like, if you want to have a chat conversation, for that, you have this particular window of OLAMA. Now close it.
PAUL: Now, once you have done the installation, simply, like, you can access that ULAM. Sometimes it might require a restart of your system.
PAUL: Okay, so you can open CMT, command prompt, yes.
PAUL: Okay, and here you can write ulama-fn version in the first step, okay, just to see that ulama is available. Now in the next step, okay, so you can do an ulama list.
PAUL: to know the models that you have downloaded, whether it's an embedding model or an LLM.
PAUL: Okay, so right now, as you can see here, she has downloaded a few embedding models here, and few, I can say,
PAUL: LLMs which are available, okay? Now, if you want to chat here directly, you can run the command ulama run. Okay, so ulama pulls helps you to download the model, ulama run, okay, and generally, like, ulama run, we do it for the LLMs, and not for embedding models.
PAUL: So, you can select one LLM. So, for example, Llama 3.2, yes, select that, the name, yes, and hit enter.
PAUL: Okay, so right now, the model is getting loaded into the memory. Okay, and now you can send a message. So, tell me about… and just write anything.
PAUL: Okay, and right now you can see that the response is coming from that.
PAUL: Okay? And if you want to close the…
PAUL: Conversation at any point of time, you can write slash buy.
PAUL: Okay, so slash byte.
PAUL: Okay, it will close the conversation. You can write just slash 5, The other slash unperform slash.
PAUL: Bye-bye. B-Y-E, bye. Bye, bye.
PAUL: Okay? And you'll be out of that. So, it's pretty much standard.
PAUL: Okay, so I think that it should be working in everybody's system, okay? So there is no such complexity here.
PAUL: Sometimes Ollama takes time to get it recognized in your command prompt, so probably a restart will do that.
PAUL: Alright, so let's get back to our discussion. I think this is my desktop 3.
PAUL: Okay, hold over.
PAUL: Okay, now this is the notebook that we'll be discussing, guys.
PAUL: Okay, so everyone open your local rag, local offline rag with Olama.
PAUL: Okay, so my model, if you can look here, so Prabhavi, I'll be working right now with Nomic.
PAUL: Okay? So I think Nomic and Gemma3, these…
PAUL: two things I think I have in the dim.
PAUL: Alright, so now let's start, executing, our,
PAUL: I think what I can do here…
PAUL: If you look into, this is exactly the same notebook. Okay, so few things are different. If you look here, the commands are there at any point of time if you want to execute them. Okay, so I've kept the commands, and previously I've told you also. So, the idea is that the model should be available in your local machine.
PAUL: Okay. Now, after that, so there is a package, Langchen Olama. The idea is that this package should be available in your system.
PAUL: So, you have to do the installation of the package. So, right here, I think, if you're working with…
PAUL: Okay, let me just activate the environment.
PAUL: Okay, now let me just open a new terminal for now.
PAUL: Okay. You read?
PAUL: Okay, so this is the name of the package, Langchen-OLAMA, and for that, you have to do a paper install.
PAUL: Okay? To access Olama from your local machine, you need this package.
PAUL: Okay, so simply you can do the installation of Langchen Ola.
PAUL: Okay, so for me, it's already there. In your case, this package won't be available, so please do the download.
PAUL: Yes, it's the same environment, I'm not doing any changes.
PAUL: Raul, I think the notebook will be there. Please have a check.
PAUL: Because I know it's in GitHub, so yes, it will be there.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Local rag ulama. Yes, the smooth book is there. Please have a check.
PAUL: Everyone.
PAUL: Because using this, you can see I will be calling two inputs. One is the embedding input.
PAUL: Okay, and the other one is the LLM.
PAUL: Okay, so that's why chat olama.
PAUL: So, Ollama embeddings and chat OLAMA, these two things. So, this package needs to be installed.
PAUL: So once you have done the installation of the package, okay, so simply you can do a confirmation, so somewhere around here, that the pack… this particular line is getting imported or not.
PAUL: How many of you could not find Olama Rap? Please let me know. It's available in GitHub.
PAUL: Now only I told you install the package, so why you are telling me that it's not, okay? So, yes, this is available in your GitHub.
PAUL: Alright, please do the installation of Olama, and then let me know. Because the rest of the stuff… in this notebook, only one change is there. Probably, I think the vector database has been changed from Faust to Chroma. Chroma is another open source…
PAUL: vector database.
PAUL: Okay, so let me know once you have done, okay? And even install this package, Langchen Chroma.
PAUL: Okay? So, langchen hyphen Chroma.
PAUL: Because I think we have the Chroma VectorDB right now, so what you can do, you can do an Langshan hyphen Chroma.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: You can do this also.
PAUL: You can add ChromaDB as the actual package.
PAUL: If you try to do, you can see for me, these are done.
PAUL: Okay, so this is a separate vector database. Last time we have used files, so this time we'll be using a separate.
PAUL: The GitHub repo link is available in Notion, please check.
PAUL: Even after installing, just be sure you are in the correct environment.
PAUL: But those are, see, the installation issues, you need to debug your own system.
PAUL: I cannot really… Check every time your system.
PAUL: Because this is pretty much standard. At any point of time, if you feel that you are not… okay, just open the Python shell, okay, and take the input, for example, this one that I have. Okay.
PAUL: And just, have a check on this one.
PAUL: So, something like this.
PAUL: Okay, if it executes without any error, it means that it's working fine.
PAUL: Similarly, I think, for Chroma also.
PAUL: If I check, okay? And these things are in your requirement also. Okay, so previously I have added it.
PAUL: If you remember, so in our requirement.txt, I think,
PAUL: you can see Langchain Chroma and ChromaDB. So, if you have require… previously, if you have installed requirement.txt, these things are, uncommented. So, I know that by default, it will be in your system.
PAUL: Okay, but if you guys have manually commented it, okay, then please do the installation.
PAUL: Can you please help us properly install the new repo?
PAUL: Just take a clone of that, create an environment, and just install the requirements.
PAUL: Vikri Musa.
PAUL: Somebody's telling, can't see the REPU link?
PAUL: See, the repo link is there. So, for example, when you open the site.
PAUL: Okay, so the first thing that is there is the GitHub repo link.
PAUL: Guys, please check at least.
PAUL: Before telling me it's not there, it's not there.
PAUL: Okay, Olama connection, Olama uses Docker, okay, so…
PAUL: For this, you need to have Docker in your system.
PAUL: Without Docker, it won't work.
PAUL: Okay, now this is the official documentation.
PAUL: Okay, so, like, this page covers, like, you have Chat Olama.
PAUL: Okay, and then comes Olama embedding, so very specifically, like, I'll be… if I try to chat with some LLMs, okay? So here you can see, so this is the package, Langchain Olama, that we have already installed.
PAUL: Okay, so a few features like tool calling and other things are available here.
PAUL: So, right here, those steps that we have discussed, like, if you want to do it in Bravo installunga for Mac, otherwise manually download it, those things that can be done.
PAUL: Okay, now this is the package that I asked you to do… install it in your local machine, Lanshan Olama, so I think that, yes, you have done it.
PAUL: Alright, and now, so this is the only one line change that I'll be doing. So, pretty much two-line change, one is basically the import, one is the LLM call.
PAUL: Only 2 line changes that I'll be doing.
PAUL: Okay, for embedding also, same thing that we'll be doing.
PAUL: Please go to Notion and check for the notebook why you are asking for the link again and again.
PAUL: Please open your Notion. In Notion, it's there.
PAUL: It's really so hard to access, so go to 22nd November, Exploring Langchen, this is the first thing you have, the repo link.
PAUL: Alright, now for the embedding second two-line change that we'll be doing, guys. Okay? So, you can see, OLAMA embeddings. So, right here, they have used a different model. We'll be using a different model.
PAUL: Okay? So just two things that will be changing.
PAUL: The rest of the things are pretty much the same.
PAUL: For Olama, you need Docker, actually. Okay, because I think you have to access a very specific port, Okay?
PAUL: So, let's start with the notebook, okay? And then, step by step, we will go through that.
PAUL: Because I think by this time, every one of you have, downloaded the models. Okay, please let me know with a thumbs up, yes, ready or not.
PAUL: Okay, alright, fine. Let's proceed now.
PAUL: I will close this test notebook. Okay, I can execute here also, not an issue.
PAUL: Olama, okay.
PAUL: Alright, so, first of all, the basic imports, just like last time we have done. Okay, so I will just do a restart of the kernel.
PAUL: Okay, because the previous executions I don't want.
PAUL: Okay, let me just take the chat window, okay? And everyone, please focus on the execution part. I will start executing the local RAGOLAMA notebook. So, you guys can open it in parallel with me. Okay, and step by step. So, the first part was the importing part.
PAUL: Okay, so let's do some basic imports, just like last time we have done it.
PAUL: So, here, if you look into, it's the same import, only one line change that we have done, which is basically the Ollama integration that we have done. Okay, other than that, everything is same.
PAUL: There is, like, no other change in the code.
PAUL: Okay, probably some change in the print statement, but I think you guys are smart enough to understand it.
PAUL: Okay, alright, so all the imports are successful, ready for local offline drag. Okay, so only one change, the embedding part and the LLM selection part.
PAUL: There is no, reason of changing the vector database, I'll just, like, see. The idea is that by this course, you should at least know 5 to 6, like, vector databases, okay? So, that's the only reason. You can use files also, I have no issues. Okay, so another change that you have is the vector DB. So, I feel that,
PAUL: like, Fires or Chroma, whichever you feel good. The idea was to showcase a new vector database, that's why I've taken ChromaDB for now. Chroma DBs…
PAUL: Also, like, it's open source, and it also has a paid version also.
PAUL: Please, Satish, can you explain runnable pass-through? So…
PAUL: This I have already told multiple times, whenever you are doing a chain execution, at that particular point of time, runnable pass-through comes into the picture.
PAUL: Alright, so now let's move ahead with the next part.
PAUL: Okay, so, for now, you can simply do a check, okay, here also in the notebook, okay, like, I'm doing an Olaman list, just…
PAUL: to have it checked, because I know that, yes, the models are available, and I can access it. But if you want, you can, simply do an olama list, I've already… okay? Now, the most important command that we have to check the connection is available or not, okay? Now, this is very, very important.
PAUL: Now, see, testing ULAMA connection, so here, test underscore LLM, I'm calling the chat olama. Chat ulama is used to connect me with an LLM.
PAUL: And for that LLM, I have selected GEMA3 1 billion. So, here I have Gemma 3 1 billion model, and temperature is equal to 0. So this is only one line.
PAUL: And once I've created, I can say the object of this class, ChatOllama, this object, I am using it, okay, and I am invoking it. Okay, say hello, I am running locally on your machine. As simple as that.
PAUL: Okay?
PAUL: Okay, now this will give you the idea that, yes, Ulama is getting connected.
PAUL: Okay, because at the end of the day, your lan chain or your Python, I can say, interpreter needs to be connected to
PAUL: through Olama.
PAUL: Yes, please let me know.
PAUL: That, for how many of you, it is working.
PAUL: Working, working, working.
PAUL: Yes, you can… if the models are downloaded in your machine, you can switch up your internet also, no issues. Everything is offline right now.
PAUL: Okay, so, like, little bit about…
PAUL: the default port which he uses, okay?
PAUL: Okay, so as you can see here, based on the port which is being used by
PAUL: Officially, like, 11434.
PAUL: Okay, so… Mmm, like, oh, llama.
PAUL: If you want to change this, okay, that is also possible.
PAUL: Let me see if I have a reference of changing the boot here. Because I know that for most of you, by default, Ulama picks up the default boot.
PAUL: So, any model that you have, you can use that for now, okay? There is no restriction. I have already told you that.
PAUL: I want to just look into the API references. As you can see here, so many models that you can work with.
PAUL: So, chat Olama.
PAUL: Okay, and here, temperature, the number of predictions… Okay, so why don't… Think that you have here.
PAUL: Nope.
PAUL: Okay, but, like, the default port which is being used.
PAUL: Okay, so it's always the, like, 11434, so this should be accessible. So, whenever OLAMA is running on… in your machine, okay, it exposes this port.
PAUL: Okay, so 11434. If it is not available, okay, then the connection that we are doing. Okay, so there can be a problem in this.
PAUL: So, simply, like, there are separate commands to check for a very specific, like, LS off. So, it depends upon the system, but the default one, LanChain, always picks up. And by default, I think that nobody has done any custom changes here, so it should be working for you.
PAUL: It's not 8080, first of all, okay? The port is different.
PAUL: Let me get rid of it.
PAUL: Olama starve also that you can do.
PAUL: Okay, at any point of time, if you feel. Kolamasarp.
PAUL: Because for me, it's already running. If it is not running, and if it's telling that, okay, please use this command olama serve from your command terminal. Okay, like CMD, or PowerShell.
PAUL: Okay, so, like, if I try to do this in my terminal, Okay, we'll let this…
PAUL: Okay, so you can see here, the port, it's telling that my port is already used. It means that Ullama is already running in this particular port.
PAUL: If it is running, okay, so LandChain automatically detects that.
PAUL: Alright guys, so right now the connection is done. Just remember, if this connection, like, this is just a test one, okay, if somehow you feel that this connection is not working, okay, then later on I have to check, like, exactly what is the issue and other stuff.
PAUL: Because there is no direct solution.
PAUL: Alright, now, let's pick up the same stuff, okay? Now, the cells that I'll be using, it is the same piece of code that we have discussed, okay?
PAUL: Now, this is the part with respect to PDF loading, so attention.pdf, same piece of code, there is no change, so directly I will execute this, because here, there is nothing to discuss. It's the same piece of code that we have done.
PAUL: Now, after this, there is a…
PAUL: Chunking operation. Again, same piece of code. Okay, if you look here, these things we have already discussed, okay? So I will directly execute it.
PAUL: Now, the main part, okay, with respect to creating embedings.
PAUL: Okay? Now, this is the part that I want you guys to focus, everyone.
PAUL: So here, embeddings is equal to OLAMA embeddings. In the import section, I have already imported this particular class of Olama embeddings.
PAUL: And here, can you see? This is the model that is available in my machine. So, an OLAMA list will tell you. So, this is the model that I have. Okay, and this is the base URL. So, if you are changing the default port, this is the default port where it is running. 11434.
PAUL: Okay? So if you are running it on some custom port, okay, then it will change.
PAUL: So, right here, so, right here, you can see that this line is commented. Okay, so it's only about the model selection that we are doing.
PAUL: And Nomic embeddings, as we can see here, we know the embedding size is 768.
PAUL: Okay? So, by default, so this doesn't support multiple sizes.
PAUL: Now, so let me just execute this.
PAUL: Okay, so here you can see.
PAUL: So right here, I have loaded the model. In the next step, so this is a sample, simple sentence that I have taken.
PAUL: And I'm converting that sentence into embedding, which is basically the sample embedding, and we are just showing you the first 10 values out of 768, just like last time we have done.
PAUL: Okay? And this is the dimension of Nomic.
PAUL: So, similarly, like, if you try to change the model, okay? So, in our case, like, if you want to change, I think.
PAUL: I can quickly do a ulama list here, okay? So…
PAUL: Olama list. Let's change the map.
PAUL: Let's take our embedding Gemma.
PAUL: Okay, so, embedding Gemma.
PAUL: Okay, it's the same thing, because, see, right now the print statement is, just showing using NUMIC embed text. You have to understand, I have to update this one, but at the end of the day, yes, this is also showing you 768, okay, this particular embedding Jemma model.
PAUL: Then, I like this MXBI, large. Okay, so let's go with this one.
PAUL: Okay, now this is a bigger model, it will take more time.
PAUL: You can see right now the dimension of, the, like, 1024, okay? Now, this particular MXBI, the mixed-grade embedding large model that we have, okay.
PAUL: So, based on that, like, you have to select, because of which one. So, right now, I'll be working with Nomic text only, so let me just take back Nomic text.
PAUL: Okay, and I will execute it. So, NUMIC is the final one for our execution, or you can play with other models also.
PAUL: The default port is 11434. You don't have to check it, it's by default.
PAUL: Alright, now, coming to the part with respect to, vector DB.
PAUL: Because my embeddings is… I will be calling these embeddings directly in the next step. So now, for the embedding part, we'll be using Chroma, okay? Very similar print statements that we have.
PAUL: So right now, the idea is to save Chroma in a folder. Okay, so for that, I am telling this is the path, the persistent directory that we are referring here.
PAUL: So, vector store is equal to chroma.
PAUL: from documents, and then I am passing the chunks, okay? Then I am passing the embeddings, so I know that my Ollama embeddings will get called. Then comes, the persistent directory where I want to save them.
PAUL: And then, the collection name. So, like, within every vector database, you have to create. Like, in some places, it is called as index, in some places, it is called as collection. Like, by default, if you have used NoSQL, in MongoDB, anybody has used MongoDB? There, also, it's called a collection.
PAUL: Like, SQL table, yes, I think you guys can refer.
PAUL: Yeah, Azure Cosmos DB, if you can think, MongoDB, it's called Collection, okay? So, based on that, so here it's called collection. So, in most of the vector databases, you'll be seeing the name, by default, like, collection or index.
PAUL: Okay, so now let me just execute this, okay, and you will see, ChromaTV folder will be created here.
PAUL: Okay, so… Okay, and now this ChromaDB folder that got created.
PAUL: Now, ChromaDB, like, it's better than Fires, I feel there, and it is used much more, like, in production.
PAUL: files is not used so much.
PAUL: Now, once we have done our embedding, so this is basically the indexing operation, so I know that within my vector database, okay, so now my embeddings are available. So in the next step, retriever.
PAUL: So let's try to do a retrieval operation.
PAUL: Okay, it's the same piece of code, there is no change here. So, Retriever, if you look, top 4K chunks, okay, it's pretty much same stuff. I'm not doing any changes here.
PAUL: Okay. Okay, and you can see here, main, query, okay, so from here, learning rates, beam size, okay, so some type of document, so this is just the retrieval part.
PAUL: So, it fetched the top 4 documents.
PAUL: Okay, now the idea is to bring our chain.
PAUL: Okay? But before bringing our chain, we need a LLM.
PAUL: Okay, because yes, I can see that I'm getting some type of retrieve docs. In the next step, I need to define the LL. So, I told you only two changes are required. One is the embedding, and one is the
PAUL: LLM. So, here you can see Chat Ollama is the class. Using this chatOllama class, you can use an LLM.
PAUL: Okay? And here, very specifically, I have selected Gemma 3 1 billion model. I know that it is available in my machine.
PAUL: So…
PAUL: Okay, and rest of the things, if you look here, okay, it's pretty much the same stuff that we have previously done.
PAUL: Okay, so, like, LLM.invoke, once the LLM is available, okay, I'm calling it. Okay, say hello, I am available.
PAUL: Okay. And the information is available inside content, okay? So, hello, I'm Gemma, running locally.
PAUL: Pretty much standard. So, only one line change. Rest of the things in your code will be exactly the same, within the chain definition that we have done, our final rag chain that we have built.
PAUL: Okay, so I will just directly copy-paste that piece of code.
PAUL: Olama should be running. You don't need to run a model. Okay, by default, OLAMA should be running, and the model should be available. You don't need to do an OLAMA run.
PAUL: Specifically, okay?
PAUL: Don't get confused. It should be only downloaded. Automatically, it accesses it.
PAUL: Alright, now the part with respect to our chain that we have worked through, okay, it's the same stuff, there is no changes there, okay? Same piece of code.
PAUL: Now, I'll be calling.
PAUL: Okay, now let's pass a query.
PAUL: Okay, and let's see how the response, because right now, I'm using a 1 billion model, so I'm not expecting a lot.
PAUL: I'm not gonna…
PAUL: Because when you are working with local models, okay? So it's telling that, okay, the document discusses the parameters used during the development of specifically focusing on learning rates, okay? Really, like, the quality of the answer that I was looking for, it's not there.
PAUL: Okay, so that's one of the things important, okay?
PAUL: Last time, if you look, when we used Gemini, the response was much better.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: So, similarly, like, if you try to change the query… okay, so here… Or what if?
PAUL: Machine learning. Let me try to ask that.
PAUL: Okay, because there are some references with respect to some document 1 and 2,
PAUL: Okay, with respect to machine learning, or probably with neural networks?
PAUL: Because of that, we are getting. But really, like, the model performance is not so much good. We can test it out with some other model also, okay, because I have few other LLMs.
PAUL: Okay, so what I can do, when I define the LLM, let's go back, okay? So…
PAUL: Olama list. This is the smallest one.
PAUL: Okay, so as you can see here, Gemma 1 billion. Okay, only 800MB. Now, let's go with some bigger models. Okay, let's go with Lama 3.2.
PAUL: Control… 3? Okay, now I'm changing the LLM.
PAUL: Okay, now,
PAUL: Based on the response, so you can see, actually, a lot of information that came from Llama. It was not only, hello, say, I am Gemma running locally, okay, as you know that, okay, so based on that, the LLM test was, hello, I'm your AI assistant.
PAUL: I don't have any physical presence in your local area, and based on that, it is responding. Really, it doesn't matter, I just need this LLM for now, so that I can pass it within our chain.
PAUL: So let me update the RAG chain here.
PAUL: Okay, and now our previous query, okay? So, what was the main topic, I think? Let's take…
PAUL: Somehow, I feel that we'll be getting better response here.
PAUL: So, these things you need to really test it out.
PAUL: The direct legal, I cannot say, like, which one.
PAUL: Okay, now it's telling that, okay, like, I… now this LLM is saying I don't know the answer based on the… however, I can try to make an educated guess. The document appears to be discussing deep learning models, so really, you can see that not work so much. Okay, based on the context that has been retrieve here.
PAUL: Really, I feel that somehow, pretty bad. Now, let's work with…
PAUL: So I hope that you can work with other models also. I have DeepSlec R1. Simply, I can write here DeepSleek R1, and the same stuff that works. Okay? But really, the performance, you really need to test it out, because I am using all bare minimum stuff, so really.
PAUL: Yes, it can be the embeddings, like Nomic, for sure. Like, it's not so much good as compared to others.
PAUL: Alright, so this was all about your local part. I think for everybody it should work, so you guys can test it out, like, how we can get better at any point of time.
PAUL: Samik Shamahajan, by default, the embedding gets initialized for your query. You don't have to do it manually.
PAUL: Here, using different models for embeddings and inferencing, so it will affect the accuracy right? Yes, for sure. If you change your embedding model, and this one, you keep on changing, you will see different results at every point of time.
PAUL: Because right now, when we are working with local stuff, all the things, it's not the best in the market. Like, when you work with OpenAI, I know it's, like, the best. I will be getting good responses. Similarly for Gemini. So I know. So here, yes, the quality of responses will be low.
PAUL: Okay, so I think for everybody that's working, please let me know with a thumbs up that, yes, the local RAG is working fine.
PAUL: Alright, lots of thumbs up, few people are telling.
PAUL: No, no, okay, a few people are there. Okay, I can look into their doubts later on.
PAUL: Alright, fine. So, this was the local version. Okay, now going forward. Okay, please don't tell me that I'm not getting response.
PAUL: If you feel that you don't have access to neither OpenAI, neither Gemini, please use a local one.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: So, this part we have done. Okay, so…
PAUL: three notebooks that we have discussed, okay, last plus this one, simple rack chain is done, and the local RAT, okay. Now, a few other notebooks are there, okay, so let's go through them once, because the idea is, let's try to complete all the things today only.
PAUL: Okay, so I think 2, 3, these are small notebooks.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Response time depends upon the model's size. If it is having higher parameters, it will take more response time.
PAUL: And for sure, the local RAM also matters.
PAUL: A little bit about document loaders that we can talk. Okay, so 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, okay, cool. So let's try to complete these things.
PAUL: These are high-level abstractions, just a simple call, and based on that, we'll be looting, okay? So, let me know, should I wait a few minutes?
PAUL: Yes, like, it's 11.15. Do you want me to start after 5 minutes?
PAUL: Moit is asking, what is the use of creating a chain when you can get answers without the chain? Great, it's totally up to you, Moith, to use the chain or don't use the chain.
PAUL: The idea of using chain was passing query, prompt, and the context, that's why.
PAUL: I'm just exploring anti-gravity. It's good. Okay, Sanjay. I really like it. I've been using it for the past…
PAUL: Once it has been released, I've been in the same stuff.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Nothing too much.
PAUL: So, Avatiga, I was asking, sorry, if it's offline, how it can generate.
PAUL: It will be using your knowledge sources, no?
PAUL: Muttasar is telling Kant Baste here.
PAUL: Okay…
PAUL: Amit Chan, where is the rag local file? I do not see. I already told multiple times, let's in GitHub, GitHub, GitHub, so many times.
PAUL: Who sees this chat? Only I look into this chat.
PAUL: And more than 200 folks are there.
PAUL: So it's a rather slow.
PAUL: for me continues, so some of the things that I pick up.
PAUL: Just download it, clone it.
PAUL: Okay, so we will start, after 3 minutes, I guess.
PAUL: In the meantime, anything's up, chat, you can let one know that.
PAUL: Somebody's asking if Olama is local, can I add DuckDuckCore? Yes, you can do that through a tool calling Nitesh. Later on, those things we'll be discussing.
PAUL: I'm having installation issues.
PAUL: Alright, fine, I'll be looking into that round.
PAUL: barrier, don't worry, okay?
PAUL: So Nali is telling, today, none of my code is working. Okay, so Nali, when I'll be ticking that out, please let me know.
PAUL: Naga, I can see other's notebook, but not that one.
PAUL: It will be in GitHub. Please have a look, Naga.
PAUL: Rahul is asking, can you please help me debunk?
PAUL: Okay, I have to look, like, when I'll be taking the routes, I'll be taking care of that route.
PAUL: Summit Mishra will discuss Drug TV? No, Drug TV…
PAUL: Right now, in today's session, nothing about Doug TV.
PAUL: Deva is asking, I posted many questions, but no response. Deva, like, this is a complete flow of chat, okay? Like, it's not like every chat that we can do. One person, if you type 5 times, just think.
PAUL: 200 students. Directly 5 to 1,000 chats, I cannot look in one shot.
PAUL: all Windows people, No, it's not all Windows people. Many people are in Mac also.
PAUL: Okay… Which indexing optimization… Mmm… Generally, during indexing, I prefer HNSW route per year.
PAUL: I'm getting issues even installation, training was, okay, alright, fine, I'll be looking into this.
PAUL: I'm not saying Ulama is not recognized, try to do a restart of your system.
PAUL: Okay… Okay, alright
PAUL: Yes, that's the idea case, like, whenever you're doing, the idea is that you should be within a virtual environment.
PAUL: Okay? It's not GitHub code, it can be any code, aka. So, any code, whether it's local, GitHub, anywhere, it's there.
PAUL: If you have, Rohit, 36GB of RAM,
PAUL: Here's higher models, you can test it out.
PAUL: Max, go for 8GB models.
PAUL: Yes, Prathamesh, in production, we do use Olama.
PAUL: It totally depends upon… if you feel your data is sensitive, yes, we always go with local-based models.
PAUL: We can use Olama, or we can host it manually.
PAUL: So, Darth is asking on the fourth note, which is load PDF document. I am getting the output as fiery not found.
PAUL: So, Dad, please check, I have sharedattention.pdf in the last class and today's class also.
PAUL: No, no, no, you cannot use all of these models with 8GB of Pram.
PAUL: Not possible, such a… Sliding window concept I'll be talking about when I'll be talking about chunking strategies, Rahul.
PAUL: Don't ask advanced topic right now.
PAUL: Aruna, can we have a discussion how to create a client-server application within Fast API out of the context?
PAUL: Are those models used in investment banks?
PAUL: No.
PAUL: They will… there will use specific algorithms, very specifically.
PAUL: If Evoloma is downloaded in local system, can we train those models further?
PAUL: Okay, fine-tuning, yes, fine-tuning can be done. Deathfish.
PAUL: There are other tools also, like Llama Factory and others using which, fine-tuning can be done.
PAUL: Alright, so… Just wait 2 minutes, okay? I will start the discussion. Please don't write in the chat.
PAUL: I won't be looking now.
PAUL: Alright, so let's get back again.
PAUL: Okay, let me just look into the chat, finally. Amit is asking, it would be good to understand fundamentally this concept, chunking, embedding, indexing.
PAUL: If these four, evaluation, we have not discussed. It will be in future sessions.
PAUL: Chunking already told in last class.
PAUL: Okay, I think, if I talk about these strategies, okay, so…
PAUL: Let's get my inside, okay?
PAUL: So, very specifically, how many of you understood chunking?
PAUL: Please let me know, step by step.
PAUL: Okay, I will just go through this part once again. What is the idea of chunking? To break bigger documents into smaller chunks.
PAUL: Bigger. Dogs.
PAUL: two small, I can say portions for now, okay? This is the core idea. And with respect to chunking strategies, that I'll be discussing in a specific lecture, okay? Because right now, I'm not, going to deep dive into that. The idea is that you know the basics of chunking.
PAUL: Those things will come into your advanced classes.
PAUL: Then, embedding.
PAUL: What is the core idea of embedding?
PAUL: the idea of converting any text into numbers, okay? So, for example, in this particular case, whatever the smaller chunks that you have, okay, so those chunks will be converted into some type of vector representation.
PAUL: This is also discussed.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Now, then comes your retrieval. Okay, so retrieval strategies we'll be talking later, but for now, the basics of retrieval that we are doing.
PAUL: Okay, because this is not even one month that we have completed. Okay, so strategies I will remove.
PAUL: Okay, so in retrieval, what happens? Based on the query.
PAUL: Okay, the query gets… so right now, we are using LanChain, okay? So the query gets automatically converted into an embedding. You have to understand this step. This is automatic, okay? And then…
PAUL: Similarity?
PAUL: Core, okay, comparison.
PAUL: in Europe.
PAUL: VectorDB?
PAUL: Okay, with respect to the different chunks that you have, because every chunk is now converted into a vector representation. Okay, so it will try to do the compare.
PAUL: Okay, so once this comparison is done, then, based on the parameter, it will find me the top K chunks.
PAUL: As simple as that.
PAUL: So this is the process of… okay, now here, similarity, so here we have used cosine similarity. There are other similarity metrics also. As simple as that.
PAUL: Why chunk in? Because, like, if the documents are big, it's very hard to convert that entire big document, so the idea is always to preserve it in smaller chunks. Okay? So pretty much these things are dynamite.
PAUL: Okay? Now, let's get back and let's start,
PAUL: Little bit about different type of file documents. This is some lanchain basics. Okay, the idea is you cover Langchain 101. Because of that, we have taken into
PAUL: account.
PAUL: The re-ranking, we'll be talking about that. Right now, re-ranking is not a priority, okay? But re-ranking is an important step when you actually try to build an advanced track. This is Nyabrak. How many of you remember the things that we have learned?
PAUL: It's something like everybody ask everything in one shot, that I want this, this, this.
PAUL: First, Nevad.
PAUL: Then, advanced drag.
PAUL: Then, modular ride.
PAUL: I hope everybody remembered the things that we are going through, step by step. Last week, we have discussed. So now we are in Nevrak.
PAUL: Okay, so don't ask about re-ranking. R-ranking comes in, Advanced one.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: So, let's try to look into, okay, so, different type of document loaders. Okay, so let's open the documentation also, because I have taken few examples. So, document loaders, line change.
PAUL: Okay? So, as you can see, based on the documentation, the same stuff. There is CSV loader, you can load CSV files.
PAUL: Okay, so now you can see here, web, unstructured… okay, unstructured is just a very specific library. I don't know how many of you know about that. During data parsing, I'll be talking about unstructured in detail.
PAUL: It's just, like, for data parsing, it is used.
PAUL: Okay, it has some paid product also. Okay, but it has an open-source version. So, this is a good product, actually, widely used in production, unstructured.
PAUL: For our data ingestion phase, you can build retail pipelines and other stuff through Unstructure, so they do have some paid product. In the free version, no such things are available.
PAUL: XML loaders, okay, directly. Okay, you can look into a few of the things which are directly available. Okay, WAV, unstructured, okay, URLs are there, sitemap is there, okay, so generally the sitemap is available in XML formats only.
PAUL: Then comes Spyder, Fire Crawl. Okay, now these are different packages. Fire crawl is used for crawling, okay, dockling, again, our data parsing library. Okay, that we'll be talking about hyperbrowser again. Like, you can… anybody knows about hyperbrowser?
PAUL: Okay, like, you can open a browser client, okay, and within that, you can do different type of searches and other stuff, and based on that, it can get the results.
PAUL: Okay, it means that you don't actually open a browser, but behind the scenes, it's open. So, it's a headless operation. So these type of things that can be done. So, for PDFs… okay, so for PDFs, you can see so many types of live data.
PAUL: Okay, so right now, like, PyPDF that we have used, the first one, but the same thing that can be achieved by Unstructured, Amazon Textract… Okay, the list is pretty much long. Docling.
PAUL: Okay, some, cloud providers, the below document loaders allow you, okay, to… from your favorite cloud providers, as you can see here, S3 directory, okay, Azure AI, Azure Blob Storage, Dropbox, okay, so a lot of functionalities are there.
PAUL: Okay, with respect to data loaders. The idea is that you'll be getting the document, first of all. To access this document, yes, from social media platforms, again, Twitter and Reddit, those type of API references are there.
PAUL: document loader with respect to messaging services, so this also, you can check it out. So, in the documentation, really, a lot of things are there, but right now, a few of the major ones that we'll be looking into that, we work with.
PAUL: So…
PAUL: always refer to the documentation, guys, at any point of time, if you feel that some particular extension that I might not have covered.
PAUL: Okay, so first of all, there are two types of loading techniques, okay, for all type of documents.
PAUL: One is the .load, which is the default one, load all the document at once. You have to understand, it takes more memory. Then comes the lazy load. So, load documents, one time. This is a generator function, so actually it uses yield.
PAUL: How many of you know the console of yield in Python?
PAUL: Yes, generator and yield.
PAUL: If you don't know about that, okay, so please have a look into that. Okay, so based on that, lazy load. I prefer, like, when you have a lot of documents, generally more than 5,000 documents, one by one, with a lot of pages, I use lazy load. Okay. Otherwise, load for generic purposes. So, for basic learning, most of the times.
PAUL: Like, load is fine. But actually, when you move into production, so lazy load is a better option in LanChain.
PAUL: Okay, so let me get some environment variables.
PAUL: Okay, so this is the same kernel that I am using, okay? And right now, if you look into, I think sample data, okay, within this, I have few type of file formats, like API, response.json, blog post.html.
PAUL: nodes.txt and product.csp. Okay, so generally, I have taken 4 examples for now. PDF we have already discussed, so we are not going to get into that.
PAUL: Now, these two parameters you guys have already seen, whether you are accessing through a PDF, okay? Like, the idea is that every document has two things, the actual content and the metadata of the document.
PAUL: Okay, so now this metadata, by default, it can be available, because sometimes there is no metadata, okay? And, generally what happens, most of the times, we create our manual metadata, and we keep it inside vector data.
PAUL: So, actually, when we'll be working in a project, I'll be showcasing those functionalities, like how to create your custom metadata.
PAUL: and push it with the embeddings. Like, every embedding should have a metadata. Then it becomes much easier to do any type of filtration operation. Okay, just like vector database operation.
PAUL: Okay, so now, this is the default one that I think you guys have previously seen in the last class also. So, this is the document class which is available directly in LanChain Core. Okay, and using this document class, so you can create
PAUL: Now, this document is a LangChain document. It means that, right now, this is not available in my local machine.
PAUL: Okay, so once you execute this, it is only available during runtime.
PAUL: Okay, so not a persistent file. So, you can see here what I have done. So, to create a document, again, two things are required. The actual content, which is the page underscore content, you can pass anything here, and then the metadata that we have created here, like source, page, author, date, okay?
PAUL: Now, based on this, I have added a few print statements just to check the type. So, what is the type of document that you have? You can see here, LangChain Port Document Page Document Class.
PAUL: Okay, so don't get confused at whether it's a PDF document, because in the source, I have kept it as example.pdf, but it's not a PDF document. This is a document which is used or created using the LangChain document class, and only available during runtime.
PAUL: Okay, now, loading with PDFs, so this part we have already gone through. Okay, so at any point of time, the PI PDF loader is pretty much good, and you can, like, work with it.
PAUL: Okay, so right now, I am loading the same attention.pdf file which we have.
PAUL: Is this load scanned PDF? No, no, no, no. Nothing is scanned here.
PAUL: Okay, and based on that, you know that Attention.pdf loaded 15 pages, what is the first page content, okay, and the metadata. Similarly, for the last page content that we have. Similarly, if you click on
PAUL: scrollable elements, so based on that, we are getting the information. Okay, so content, first 200 characters, and there is an else statement. If the PDF is not found, then it will raise an exception, as simple as that. So, because of that, I have kept this particular print statement.
PAUL: Not added an exception, but a simple else condition.
PAUL: Okay, so this part you guys have already done in our previous two notebooks. Okay, pretty much standard.
PAUL: Now, working with Lazy Rudy. Okay, now this can be something new.
PAUL: And now, like, this should be used always, like, when you… when you are working with very big and large documents at any point of time.
PAUL: Like, this is the most optimal way. Otherwise, okay, for example, there can be RAM issues if you are not using lazy looting.
PAUL: But there is no actual changes, only the change, if you look into the calling, the loader calling. Okay, it means that previously in the loader.
PAUL: I used directly, like, load. Okay, if I show you here, you can see here, it's directly loader.load.
PAUL: So I've defined the loader, and I'm directly loading it. So, similarly, here, you can pass a lazy loot.
PAUL: Yes, async call, I can make it manual.
PAUL: There is no restriction in that.
PAUL: Those things are manual.
PAUL: So, right here, based on the PTF, okay, pH one by one versus the first three PHAs only. Okay, so that's why the first three things that are coming into the part.
PAUL: So it gives you much more power, I feel, at any point of time, rather than looking into the entire PDF. If your PDF is of 50,000 pages, okay, you don't want everything to be loaded in one shot. Rather than, okay, doing a lazy loading is an optimal way of loading stuff into the memory.
PAUL: Okay, so that's why I hope everybody understood, okay? It's not about reading the entire PDF, but you are actually going through very specific, the first 3 pages right now. So this is the block, so if I change it to 5,
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: So you can just look, look into… so I'm just reading the 5 pages only, not all those 15 pages. Okay? Much more memory-efficient task at any point of time.
PAUL: Yes, any time retrieval, I cannot say, anytime you have to define a particular logic. So, for example, if you are browsing through, okay, the idea is you, a 50,000 pages document. Okay, you read first 100 pages, then 100 pages, then 100 pages in that way, through a badge that you'll be defining.
PAUL: Then in the next step, so this piece of code, previously also we have discussed, where we pass a folder, and you can read multiple PDFs also.
PAUL: Okay, so here, PDFs is the folder that I have. Okay, so this is the PDF folder, and two folder, two files are there, rag.pdf and ragsurvey.pdf, okay? And here, I'm passing the name of the directory, which is basically the PDFs.
PAUL: Okay, so if passed, so this is a simple check, whether it exists or not, and then loading the PDF from this particular directory, PDF underscore directory that we have.
PAUL: Now, I'm creating a blank list. Within this blank list, I'll be, like, performing an operation of adding the documents one by one.
PAUL: Okay, so find all the PDF files. Okay, so that's why this is a list operation. The idea is that, I'm looking for only star.pdf. Okay, it means that all types of PDF files only.
PAUL: Okay, so this is a glob operation that I am doing. This is pretty much Pythonic stuff, nothing related to Langchain. Okay, so here, the idea is to simply, like, filter out the .pdf files.
PAUL: Okay? And based on that, now, if I change this extension, okay, then I'll be getting zero files, because right now, I'm just looking for PDF files only. Okay, so for example, here you can see, found two PDF files. Now, if I change it to .txt, okay, so simply we'll see that there are no TXT files here in this directory.
PAUL: Okay, you can see zero PDF files. See, PDF is a print statement that we have, so don't get confused. Okay, so this is a simple print statement, and this number is dynamic that I have kept it.
PAUL: So right now, in our case, it's PDF.
PAUL: So, what we have done? So, first of all, selected the directory, looking for a chat. Yes, that directory is available or not. Okay, then we have created a blank list. The idea is that we'll be appending all the paths there.
PAUL: Okay, then we are performing a list operation. On top of that, we have added a glob. Okay, so using glob, you can do a filtration of different type of file formats. Then it's printing. Print found, the total number of files based on the file format that we have.
PAUL: Now, for PDF file in PDF files, okay, now the idea is that for each PDF file, I am loading it.
PAUL: One by one. So that's why there is a for loop which is available here. Okay, and this all documents that I have, you can see that extend operation that I am doing, so I'm actually adding everything here. Okay, so this is a simple extend operation with respect to list.
PAUL: You can finally print loaded, so one by one, all of the PDFs will be loaded, and finally return the length of all the documents, the length of the PDF, okay? And those things will be printed out. And finally, we are, like, right now, as you can see here, the metadata also, we are looking into the actual source
PAUL: Okay? Within that particular document, so those things will be…
PAUL: Coming into picture, you can see. So right now, from the metadata, I have extracted only the sources, rag.pdf and ragsurvey.pdf, that I have.
PAUL: Okay, and other than that, two PDFs are loaded. The first PDF was having 19 pages, the second PDF was having 21 pages. So, similarly, you can load multiple types of file at any point of time with different types of file format. You have to understand you can manipulate this particular section.
PAUL: Okay, so it can be, like, start.pdf.txt, you can play with this file.
PAUL: Now, coming to the next part of, like, loading CSV files.
PAUL: Do lazy load, one page at a time? No, like, you have to write the condition, how many pages you want to load during lazy load. Narula, whoever is asking.
PAUL: Now, people are asking, lazy loader is only applicable when the content is being loaded into the…
PAUL: This is for reading the documents, reading the documents, guys.
PAUL: This is a document loader. It means that when you are loading the document, this lazy load is available, not during vector TV.
PAUL: Yes, the idea is that you should always have your decision-lossing memo. Whenever you are implementing lazy loading, the idea is you select the numbers based on the memory and the infrastructure that you
PAUL: Okay, so generally it's within the Docker, I can say, instance that it will be running.
PAUL: Okay, most of the times, we keep, like, 500 pages in one shot.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Yes, you can load everything in one shot and load it into VectorDB, there won't be any type of problem.
PAUL: Will it able to read screenshots or images as a part of the document? No. For that, you have to use custom logics.
PAUL: Okay, so those things we'll be talking during data bars in.
PAUL: For now, the idea is that it's simple, text for now, whatever is there with respect to text. I'm not working with respect to images for now.
PAUL: I'm asking, can this document module load scanned PDFs? Yes, why? It cannot load. At the end of that scanned PDF, all that matters to me is the extension. Whether it's scans, whether it's created, it doesn't matter to me.
PAUL: Okay, but I will say the performance will be very, very bad. If you have a scanned PDF, I will perform some type of OCR operation, and then I will get the content, and that will be my way. But you can pass it. But generally, the parsers won't work so much good. You have to understand this.
PAUL: There is nothing called as best Modith. You have to do experiments.
PAUL: Okay, so, alright, let's come to our next step with respect to a CSV file. So, there is a CSV file that I have, which is basically the products.csv.
PAUL: Okay, so…
PAUL: Okay, so based on the loader, as you can see here, CSV loader, there is a direct class which is available within the document loaders, and I am passing it. SampleData slash product.csv, gath, okay, and then I am loading it.
PAUL: Okay, and very specifically within that, like, source column, which is very specifically the product name. Which column to use as a source in metadata? So, for that, I have very specifically passed it, like, source column. It becomes one of the major metadata. Let me see if I can open this product.csv, okay?
PAUL: Rainbow.csv, let me just install it.
PAUL: Okay, looks like… okay, yes, it coordinated.
PAUL: Okay, so this is basically the file. Okay, and you can see product ID, product name, category, description, livestock. A simple CSV file, how it looks like, so based on that.
PAUL: Wow, we are performing this.
PAUL: Okay, so CSV loaders, like, you can perform multiple queries. So right now, if you look into, so once we have loaded, like, all the rules.
PAUL: So, right now, based on that, so each column, you have to understand, like, not each column, each row, okay, it becomes.
PAUL: Like, you can think about the total number of rows is equal to the total number of products that you have.
PAUL: So, based on that, so, like, 15 products, okay, based on 15 rules that I have, and very specifically, you can select, okay, like, yeah, other things with respect to CHB that you can manipulate.
PAUL: through other libraries also, I've seen people manipulating through pandas, Polars. Okay, as you know, there are other data manipulation libraries, and then you can bring your data back to LandChain, so that is also possible.
PAUL: Now, inspecting the first 3 products, so very specifically. Okay, so based on that, so product 1, okay, product ID, okay, so everything that is available in the CSV file, you can load it.
PAUL: Okay, so step by step, if you want to do a parsing operation for a very specific column, that is also possible. You can see here row 0, row 2, in that way, like, 15 products that we have loaded into the memory, and we are only printing out the 3.
PAUL: Okay? Because, really, if you look into… can you tell me, like, how lanchain is getting used here? See, if you're… this is the input statement of LanChain.
PAUL: This is the other statement of Langchain, and this is linechain.
PAUL: Other than that, everything here is pretty much… Python.
PAUL: How many of you can understand this? It's not entirely langchain code. It's pure Python, which is written here.
PAUL: Please let me know that.
PAUL: Because people are telling so much language in code. It's simple print statements that I have added, so that you guys can understand the output at any point of time. So, actually, if you think about when I'm working, it will be just one line.
PAUL: Okay, then the path… okay, then comes the loading, because these are few checks, and checks are not necessary. You can directly do a loading operation.
PAUL: And it will be loaded into the memory, okay? So that's why. At the end of the day, it's pretty much 3 lines only.
PAUL: Okay, now, this is for custom CSV loaders, okay? So, like, if you want to use it at any point of time, very specifically, for any type of configurations that you have, okay, because using this CSV loader.
PAUL: So right now, the same file, okay, but manually, we have changed few of the things.
PAUL: So, right now, in our custom configuration, the file path, okay, which is the CSV path that I am passing, samples underscore data slash product dot CSV, now CSV arguments. Now, these are arguments that we have not discussed previously. Okay, now, what type of delimiter? You know that in CSV file also, delimiter can be changed
PAUL: Yes or no?
PAUL: We know that it's a comma-separated file, by default, but it's not necessary.
PAUL: Okay, just think about if you have brought a TSV file, tab-separated file, then
PAUL: Okay, so that's why. So these things are the…
PAUL: provided. Okay, then the, field names, use the first row at headers.
PAUL: I think this is a common operation when you define a header, if you have worked with pandas, Polars, everywhere the same stuff that we do.
PAUL: And then finally, you are loading the document. So, these are a few arguments. Now, this, you can always look into the API reference of CSVLoad.
PAUL: Okay, so you can actually manipulate with… it's not about, reading everything, so very specifically, you can read specific columns also.
PAUL: So those operations can also be done.
PAUL: Now, working with JSON files, I feel that most of the time, JSON is one of the most important ones.
PAUL: Because we always work with JSONs.
PAUL: in production.
PAUL: So…
PAUL: sample data, JSON API response, okay? So, this is, right now, like, an API version, okay, so ID, author, based on data, sample data, which has been generated. You can see right now, tags and other stuff.
PAUL: Okay, now let's try to read this.
PAUL: So, directly, the JSON loader class is there, okay, and then I am passing the file path.
PAUL: And right now, you can see file path, JSON. Okay. And very specifically, extract each article. Can you see here? So, from that JSON file.articles, if you look here.
PAUL: There is the article option.
PAUL: Okay, so this particular… so this is the key that I have passed there. Anything that's within the articles, it will be extracted.
PAUL: I think everybody knows about JSON, a key-value pair. It's pretty much common.
PAUL: Okay, and most of the times in production, we work with JSON.
PAUL: So, extracting each article, and context, text content… okay, return the full JSON for each of the articles, okay? The idea is that we are not extracting the content, because the content is not directly available. It's a nested one. Nested inside this AK New Hunt.
PAUL: If it was direct, then you can use… the option was text contact.
PAUL: Okay, so let me just load it. Okay.
PAUL: And… okay, no module named JQ. Alright, this JQ, I need to install it.
PAUL: Okay, so just to be cool.
PAUL: Install JQ.
PAUL: Now I think it should be working, yes.
PAUL: So, now you can see, loaded the 5 articles, okay, content, the entire thing, that came from there, okay, so we are actually looking into everything. The first article, 001, Introduction to WAG.
PAUL: Okay, so introduction to RAM. So, this was the first element that we have printed it out, and you can see document 0.
PAUL: Okay, so it means that from Article 0, that it will pick up.
PAUL: And in the metadata, by default.
PAUL: in the metadata, the path of the file, which is basically the API response, and sequence number one.
PAUL: This is a manually created metadata, okay?
PAUL: By default, which is available.
PAUL: JQ, it's a package which is… which you need whenever you are working with JSON loaders in LangChain. Okay, so using that JQ, you try to do the parsing. So that's why that JQ package you need to install.
PAUL: Okay, so if you want, Obviously, if I swing.
PAUL: J, Q.
PAUL: can sleep.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: And very specifically, as they have very specifically told architectures on Linux and macOS.
PAUL: Windows, they are not good.
PAUL: Okay, so I don't think in Windows you need to do the installation. You guys can let me know if you're doing it on Windows.
PAUL: at any point of time, to read the JSON files to understand. Okay, so because of that, you have the Python bindings that are available for JSON. So that is the actual package, which helps you to do the parsing of JSON. So that's why that was important.
PAUL: Windows also needed the installation, alright.
PAUL: Now, finally, okay. Now, similar operations, okay, like extracting specific fields.
PAUL: Okay, because previously, if you remember, I was extracting everything.
PAUL: Within, the article key. Article was the key, within that, whatever the values were there, we are extracting. Okay, but right now, we want to go much more nested, so that's why .content also we have taken. Okay, it means that first it will go into articles, then we'll move into content.
PAUL: Okay, and right now we can see the value here. It's a text, so we can use, now, text underscore content is equal to true. Okay, so which will be, treated as plain text for now, and now it will be loaded.
PAUL: Okay, so…
PAUL: Yes, so based on that, we are just reading the first two only. Okay, and right now, you can see rack systems work while first retrieving the relevant documents and vector databases.
PAUL: Okay, so you can see here, rack systems work, this one, and vector databases. So, we are actually extracting specific parts. So, all those functionalities are available, if you want to use that, okay?
PAUL: And, see, this is the JQ syntax that I have kept it, okay?
PAUL: It helps in parsing only, just like a GPS for JSON, through this .articles.articles. So, after installing this, you can use towards the Python bindings.
PAUL: Then, HTML is also there.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Hmm.
PAUL: Okay, so there is a package installation of unstructured. Okay, so let me see…
PAUL: Okay, for HTML loading, it is unstructured HTML loader is there, alright.
PAUL: Okay, you can do the installation of this package unstructured. Okay, so unstructured is used for data parsing.
PAUL: Okay, for now, it's data parsing, but in the actual product, a lot of other things are also leery.
PAUL: So, using unstructured, you can read multiple types of files and other stuff. Pretty much a data parsing library, I can see.
PAUL: Okay, so let me complete this one. Okay, so just a similar loader. So, here you can see unstructured HTML loader that I have. Okay, and using this, I'll be passing it directly. So these things are just, like, really, it doesn't matter.
PAUL: Going forward, that whether we'll be working with HTML files, if you have done a lot of scrapping operation, then also I feel. Because right now, LLM scrappers are really great working with, so directly working with HTML files, really not so much important. But yes, the options are there at any point of time.
PAUL: Then, you have your web page loader. Okay, so this is directly available where you can pass URLs, and based on that, you can get some type of information. So, here, as you can see, Langchain, okay, so I think I can…
PAUL: I'm not using this URL circuit.
PAUL: Okay, so here you can see Note only works with static HTML and no JavaScript rendering. Okay, so really, like, WebPaste Loader, not so much powerful, because it can only extract static content. And right now, in 2025, most of the websites are dynamic. They are using Next.js.
PAUL: Okay, or react in production. So really, but yes, using this also you can do. Okay.
PAUL: Okay, and if you want to look into the actual content which is available in this URL, so we are just printing out the content of page 1 and the content of page 2.
PAUL: Then, working with text files and markdown files.
PAUL: Same standard, only this, you can see, like, text loader that came into the picture. So it's all about the change in the import. Rest of the thing is exactly the same. There is no such major changes. I hope everybody understands, these are just easy stuff that you guys can play with.
PAUL: Really, like, similarly for README files, under unstructured, you have a direct loader, which is the unstructured Markdown loader. Same stuff, you have to pass that, you have to read the files. So, the idea was to show you that,
PAUL: You can load multiple type of file formats, and really, when you are working, so there can be different types of file formats, really. And everything, you can load it in one shot and pass it in your vector database.
PAUL: Okay, so that is also possible.
PAUL: But generally, it's a bad practice. The idea is that you should always remove the noise. Okay, so you should always look into the actual content or the context that is required for your retriever, rather than looking into junk.
PAUL: Okay, we don't want noise, so because of that, it's always a good practice to
PAUL: Do a filtration operation of your different type of file formats.
PAUL: Okay, so now, see, batch loading, with directory loader. Okay, so this directory loader, I feel that you might work with it, it's just like, rather than using, loop by yourself, you can use the directory loader.
PAUL: If you remember last time, I created a folder, and I then used a for loop. But in directory loader, you don't need a for loop, it takes care of that. And if you remember, glob is equal to start.txt. So right now, I'm just looking into the txt files.
PAUL: Okay, so this is one way. So, loading entire document libraries, processing multiple files at once, building knowledge bases. So, for that, it is required.
PAUL: And, most of the times, I will say, in our project, we will be working with directory mode.
PAUL: Inside directory loader, we'll be keeping a logic that it will be reading PDF files, Python files, Markdown files, MDX files, okay, different type of IPYMB files. Okay, so different type of file formats that we can read it.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Now, loading multiple file types. So, right now, this is a custom function that we have.
PAUL: Okay, now, whenever we are working, so here, you can see that this function is responsible to load these many file types. So I always prefer using custom functions
PAUL: Okay, it's always better at any point of time. And keep things modular, so that if you want to change your loader, if you feel that the parsing is not good. So, this is a simple document, and in that particular document, you can see I'm loading PDF, then text, CSV, JSON. So, one by one, all the functions
PAUL: That I have. If you look into PyPDF loader, then I have my text loader, then I have my CSV loader, then I have my JSON loader, and everything in one shot.
PAUL: Okay, so this is the function which is responsible to do. Okay, and now, it told me that, okay, for TXT files, there is node.txt. For CSV files, there is products.csv and JSON, this one. Total, 17 documents loaded.
PAUL: And the actual number of files which has been loaded is 3. But the documents, okay, it comes with the PDFs and the pages, that's why the document becomes 17.
PAUL: Alright guys, so… Right now, majorly, okay, the document 17 count will come, just remember, 15,
PAUL: Okay, from this CSV, and one from this TXT, and one from JSON.
PAUL: Okay, so how this 17 number comes? Okay, so because herein, every row is treated as a document, right? That's fine.
PAUL: Alright, I think we will keep, this today. It's already 12, okay, I can discuss that.
PAUL: Text splitting… Hmm… It's already 12, okay? So, let's go through this tomorrow.
PAUL: Tomorrow, we'll complete then 3, 4, 5, 6, 7.
PAUL: Alright, I can start taking the routes.
PAUL: Okay, now you guys can ask, if I have a data frame, numpy array, dictionary renovation.
PAUL: No, directly also you can loot it, it's not necessary. BS class over, it's 12, so I will complete it, because I want to complete the tops, otherwise I have to take that, extra session, I don't want an extra session.
PAUL: Alright, now… Okay, so you guys can start raising your hand one by one. I will start unmuting.
PAUL: Okay, so people who have doubts, please let me know. If somebody is getting a module not found error, please install the module, Boench Sharma.
PAUL: This is a Python error, not a error with respect to Lansion or AI.
PAUL: Alright, so let's start with, Satyavrata, Rajat Kana, then comes to Prathmesh.
PAUL: Then I will come to Sanali, then, Michael Sampath, few people I have unmuted, so one by one. Please, guys, go.
Satyabrata: Yeah. Yeah, hi, Paul. My question is, like, for the embedding, right? In the Olama side, we use, you know, make embedding one.
Satyabrata: And for the, element, we used the,
PAUL: The Gemma one. The Gemma. Oh, the Gemma, yeah, yeah.
Satyabrata: Jamathi, yeah. But what I understood from your, earlier, theoretical class, right, the embedding, whichever we are using the embedding to part, create the embedding for the documents, or the external data.
Satyabrata: should be the same model, to be used embedding for the query. But here, the query is not being embedding using the Nomic embed text, right? I think the query is being used, embedding by the Gemma 3 only. So how…
PAUL: EMA3 is an LLM, it's not an embedding model.
Satyabrata: But the query we are passing, right, how it's getting embedded within, the query.
PAUL: The action automatically handles it. You don't.
Satyabrata: Okay.
PAUL: worry, you have to define the embedding once. It knows that, okay, if I have done the… during the retrieval, that process, so I will be using for the query also.
Satyabrata: Okay, okay, the same model, it will understand, it'll use for the query in…
PAUL: If you have defined only one model, then how other model will come?
PAUL: Just think about that. We have only defined one embedding model.
PAUL: So, how another embedding… so, just think, which is another embedding model that you were thinking?
Satyabrata: No, no, I'm not thinking embedding model, but I'm thinking the LLM we are using Gemma, right? I think it is only embedding.
Satyabrata: No, they…
PAUL: How you can think an LLM is an embedding model.
Satyabrata: Okay, got it, got it, yeah, yeah, yeah. The same model it will take and do the embedding of the query.
PAUL: The limiting model has a different purpose. LLM model has a different purpose.
PAUL: I can say both of them models.
PAUL: But one is used totally for a different task, one is used totally for a different task. I hope you got your point.
Satyabrata: Yeah, yeah, that's true.
PAUL: Alright, fine, Satut.
Rajat Khanna: Yeah.
Satyabrata: Just to…
PAUL: Yeah, something like that. 10.
Satyabrata: Yeah, suppose.
PAUL: Yeah, something.
Satyabrata: Yeah, yeah. So, we have two phases, right? Suppose, in my project, the first I'm doing the embedding. In my next phase, I'm doing my generation, right? While doing the phase to generation, if I'm not passing any model by which model I used for the embedding, then how it will consider the model I used, suppose
Satyabrata: 3-month work, I did my embeddings for the external data, but now I'm just doing the general summary. So, how it will understand, like, which model I used for the embeddings? In this case, Paul?
PAUL: Your embedding models will always be fixed. You don't change your embedding models every day.
PAUL: Okay. It is always fixed. Before 3 months, you were.
Satyabrata: No.
PAUL: Nomic. Okay. Now, during generation, you will be always using NOMIC.
Satyabrata: Okay, I got it.
PAUL: You can't change suddenly.
PAUL: Then…
Satyabrata: Okay, good.
PAUL: Vector creation formula that will change, and your results will be, like, highly impacted.
Satyabrata: Okay, okay, good one.
PAUL: Call the similarity score algorithm will fail.
Satyabrata: Okay, okay, okay, okay, got it, got it. Then we have to keep it fixed right now.
PAUL: Yes, you have to… that is the first thing. When you start a project, you decide, okay, this is a long-term thing. I know that for the next 3 years, this will be fixed. Otherwise, a lot of things that needs to be changed.
Satyabrata: Good, good, yeah, thanks.
PAUL: All right.
Michael Sampath: There's a follow-up question on the same thing. So, let's say I've chosen the normic embedding model.
Michael Sampath: And I've done my work for one year, and it created a Chroma DB.
PAUL: Okay.
Michael Sampath: if I'm trying to… tomorrow, there's a new embedding model that comes, which is really more efficient. So I'm replacing my Nomic to a new model.
Michael Sampath: So, will I have to create the ChromaDB again?
PAUL: Yes, you have to perform your entire indexing operation. Again.
Michael Sampath: So that'll be a problem, okay. And I have two follow-up questions, I mean, not follow-up, two additional questions. We were talking about PDF, text, CSV, JSON, HTML. How about Word?
PAUL: You have to look for doc OLC if you directly don't have a library, like, if something is directly not available in Langchen. You have to look for a custom library, do the installation, read the file, get the content passed to Langchen.
Michael Sampath: Perfect, we'll do that. And the third, last, third, last question is, this offline model, Llama and the ChromaDB,
Michael Sampath: Is it…
PAUL: It's not a module, it's a vector domain.
Michael Sampath: Yeah, yeah, VectorDB. I mean, Llama and the VectorDB.
PAUL: Is it enterprise-worthy? Yes, Chroma has an enterprise version. You have to pay, I think, close to… some pricing model it has. Like, pay-per-you-go is there. Enterprise version is there of Chroma. Chroma is used in production.
Michael Sampath: In production, but when I… when you say ChromaDB, I mean, when I say ChromaDB, offline version is an enterprise version, right?
PAUL: Generally, what we do, if we want to host it and keep it in our own infrastructure, it is scalable, there is no issue in that.
Michael Sampath: Okay, perfect. Thank you.
PAUL: But you have to manage everything. For a managed service, they take a charge. You have to understand. For the managed service, they take a charge, but if you host it in your own cluster, no issues.
Michael Sampath: Okay, perfect. So, man, my intention is not to have internet access at all.
PAUL: What have you?
Michael Sampath: more BP.
PAUL: Yes, yes, it can be in your own AWS and your own cloud infrastructure hosted, no issuing.
Michael Sampath: Sure. Thank you.
Rajat Khanna: Rajad Desai.
PAUL: Rajat Yagoret.
Rajat Khanna: So, I have a few flow questions. Flow as in step-by-step, how the things work. So, my, one normal question is, like, do we really need to create, environment, separate environment, or…
Rajat Khanna: Like, we can, run all the code normally, like, all the packages are installed locally, and we can work with them without creating any environment.
PAUL: really meant… this is a Python question.
Rajat Khanna: No, yes, yes, yes. So, just, just a normal…
PAUL: This is a practice.
Rajat Khanna: For every project, the idea is that.
PAUL: You should have separated, isolated virtual environments.
Rajat Khanna: Okay.
PAUL: That is a practice. But, like, during in class, I can do, like, I've created an environment, and for the next 5 classes, the same environment is going on, but when I'll be working on projects, every time I'll be creating a specific environment.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, and now the other question is, like, like, we have used, Chroma VectorDB, so, like, normally, we install, DBs, so, like VectorDB, there are other DBs as well, so we need to do configuration if we are using other VectorDBs locally.
PAUL: Yes, yes, correct.
Rajat Khanna: Okay. And, while we have created, like, we have uploaded a few documents, like PDF documents, and used different embedding models.
Rajat Khanna: for the same, PDF file, created different embeddings and different, vector DBs for those environments. Now, while using a LLM model, can we, use multiple vector DBs, with the same Python code?
PAUL: Yes, you can use multiple vector TBs. Okay. Like, you have to create multiple retrievers in that particular condition.
PAUL: Because one retriever will be responsible for one vector DB, the other retriever will be for other vector DB in that way.
Rajat Khanna: Okay.
Rajat Khanna: And the last question is, like, for example, we are, rather than doing everything in local, we are doing everything in AWS. So, so same thing, like, configuration and all those things, all things will be chargeable, and then how we will be creating and CICD, all these things work. So, like, there will be, config… different configuration that we need to go through, right?
Rajat Khanna: as in means we have created a different environment in AWS, and then we are paying for VectorDBs, to store the data, we are paying for, like, different LLMs, and then all the things works, and then that will be hosted in our, you can say, host, hosting all the application in AWS.
PAUL: Yes, like, through different services, you have to integrate all those to build your final solution.
Rajat Khanna: Whether it can be custom hosting or AWS resources directly you are consuming.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, okay. So, normal in, enterprise, in working in a company, so, I have not worked, in, like, these solutions, so you might be have a better idea, like, they will be using, virtual environments, virtual environment as in AWS or Azure environment, rather than doing everything.
PAUL: It's not… see, it doesn't matter. Virtual environment in cloud, if you're working with Python, then you have to maintain.
Rajat Khanna: Okay.
PAUL: Depth one does it similarly for others also. If you are working with NPM, there will be a package.json within which all the packages that you are using for your NPM project will be there. So that's why it's a common standard for every, like, every programming language.
Rajat Khanna: No, no, no, no.
Rajat Khanna: No, question is not for the programming language, question is for, enterprise, like, companies, how company, means after, means we get our knowledge, we will be giving interviews to the companies. So, my question is, like, companies are using, mostly, doing the code in the, AWS, like, cloud environment?
PAUL: Oh, right. So, for example, in AWS, if you're working, probably, like, you might have created a script, or if you're using something like AWS SageMaker, within your SageMaker, you can go, you can write the entire code, and everything. There, within that, VS code is available.
PAUL: So the entire environment, you can call it up, you can attach it with your lambdas and other stuff that you can do.
PAUL: It's cloud-specific, you have to understand. It changes with every cloud.
Rajat Khanna: Okay.
PAUL: But your main logic will always remain the same. It means the actual programming language, for example, Python. Python code doesn't change it, it's only about the environment that changes. I hope you get that.
Rajat Khanna: Yes, yes, yes. So, just the last question is, it's just a personal, information question, like, I have, cleared the certification of Azure AI Engineer Associate, as well as AWS AI Practitioner.
Rajat Khanna: So, the next step, like, I can only go for one, certification on the next level, either with the Azure or AWS, so which on the enterprise level will be more efficient, like, while giving…
PAUL: In 10 markets, majorly, the organizations are working with Azure and AWS, so, like, you have already done both for anyone. Probably in AWS, you can go ahead with the data science speciality track, or in AWS ML Speciality Track, something like that, you can take it.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, okay, yeah, that's… thank you, thank you, Paul.
PAUL: Alright, next.
Prathmesh Atre: Hello, sir.
PAUL: Yes, Patmish.
Prathmesh Atre: Sir, my question is, like, are we, as you said, like, we will be using the Olama only for, like, for embeddings and chat? Are we even using that for our next actual projects that we are building? Because, when…
PAUL: I will be always using OpenAI. Now, you have to do the configuration for Rulong.
Prathmesh Atre: Right, right? That is what I'm asking, because when it comes to local things, it's fine to use these kind of things, but when we try to productionize, deploy these things, it's always better.
PAUL: Production also, you can use Olama, there is no restriction in that.
Prathmesh Atre: That is fine, sir, but it, brings a, you know, kind of excessive memory requirement and, time to…
PAUL: setup area in front. See, that's why.
Prathmesh Atre: array.
PAUL: In long term, if you think about OpenAI will charge you much more, but it's a one-time setup. You might need to spend a few weeks, but once you have you done that, I know in long term, that will be much more cost-optimized.
Prathmesh Atre: Right, and also, it will take some more time to, you know, process the things in our overall project, because when.
PAUL: So now you can see that the latency will be higher, but really, at the end of the day.
PAUL: When you are working in a project on…
PAUL: When you are in a leadership position, okay, so, like, you have to take the
PAUL: It's like, money, time, this thing, there has to be a trade-off, so it's totally…
Prathmesh Atre: and so…
PAUL: Depends upon the budget.
Prathmesh Atre: Also, sir, I just, have given, actually, some feedbacks, you know, on the community chat a little too, for the next courses. Hope you will take those into consideration, like, voice data.
PAUL: Good morning, Danny.
Prathmesh Atre: content.
PAUL: Voice AI, it's easy, man, it's API. You can directly check out Eleven Labs, you can install the package of that, and you can integrate it for TTS tasks, STT tasks. Really, like, those are third-party stuff. That is one… like, it's… I can integrate it any day.
PAUL: It's just a small thing, just 3 to 4 lines of code that I have to do.
Prathmesh Atre: That's true, sir, but when it comes to actual, you know, comprehensive project based on voice only, then it's a, you know, complex task, and not just of 3-4 lines of code, you know? It totally depends upon the task. Right, right, that is…
PAUL: what type of task you are doing, everything is in real time, then it's different, okay? Right, right. But that's why, like, see, right now, the next course will be data science, so it won't be there. Probably after 3 or 4 months, like, when your course will be near completion, then you can give me a reminder.
PAUL: Wanda. Then, probably, like, background… Add that.
PAUL: That's just funny.
Prathmesh Atre: 11 Labs is for a lot of things, like text-to-speech, speech-to-text, and voice agents. So, the conversion is not important, like text-to-speech or speech-to-text, but the real-time continuous communication, like, we are talking now with each other. So, that kind of communication, they are provided through their voice agents. So, that specific part, is what I'm saying, and which is important.
PAUL: See, that's a niche requirement, you only have. Now, tell me, in this industry, who is using 11LA? It's not everybody. They will be taking the services very specifically from their cloud providers.
PAUL: people don't move, that's why, like, if some organization is working with AWS, he or she will always stick to AWS. So probably the AWS features will be used much more, or Azure features will be used much more. Okay, so that's why, like, it becomes a niche requirement only for you. Similarly, like, I prefer Assembly AI much more.
PAUL: Okay, I feel that the… somehow, with respect to cost and other stuff, because 11 Lab is very costly. Somebody is building a product? No. I know, like, for a long time.
Prathmesh Atre: $11 per month, like, the starting of it. $5, $11.
PAUL: That is for general users, I'm talking when you use it in production.
Prathmesh Atre: Enterprise, like, more than…
PAUL: It is very, very costly. That's why, like, I don't prefer. There is an alternate.
Prathmesh Atre: Asimated AI is good, sir, but it's just, like, you know, convergent kind of task it is doing, and not the AI-based voice-related tasks.
PAUL: Okay, now it's your specific requirement, that's why.
PAUL: You cannot tell your requirement directly is your everybody's requirement.
Prathmesh Atre: No, I'm not saying, just it's kind of new thing related to Void, that's why I said that.
PAUL: rental ad account.
Prathmesh Atre: in the next room.
PAUL: you can create a POC, okay, and you can showcase. If you got stuck anywhere, you can let me know, then I can help you out, okay?
Prathmesh Atre: Okay, sir.
PAUL: Alright, let's move to next participant, Sonali. I think, Sonali, you were having some installation issues.
Sonali: Leah, I have… Yeah, I have issues regarding installation.
PAUL: Can I share my screen? Nitesh, Rahul Parihar…
PAUL: Then comes, Krishna Santra, Kiranrathur, Hari Kuma.
Sonali: Do I share? I don't see the share option.
PAUL: Wait, wait, I will add you to panelist.
PAUL: Okay, yes. In the meantime, others who have a direct question, they can let me know.
PAUL: If you want to share your screen, please let me.
Hari Kumar: You and I won.
PAUL: Alright, Mohit. Okay. That is fine, like, you can look into the import part. Generally, most of the document letters come from Lanshan underscore community.
PAUL: That is the actual one. The older version is from Langshan.document, okay?
PAUL: The recent one, yes.
PAUL: Yes, anybody else? Like, others? Ari, I'm sure a direct question is here, so you can…
Hari Kumar: I want to share my screen soon.
Sonali: Can you see my screen?
PAUL: Yes, I can share your screen.
Sonali: I'm sharing my screen.
PAUL: Alright, I can see, I can see the zoom window.
Sonali: So earlier I got this…
Sonali: Yeah, so earlier, I got this LangChain not installed and all, but if you see, it is already installed, pip show Langchain, everything is installed here.
Sonali: But still, when I run this.
Sonali: And now I'm running, it is just going into loop, and it's not completing. But earlier I was getting nothing is installed.
PAUL: So, what is the environment?
Sonali: Oh.
PAUL: I can see my ENP kernel that you are using.
Sonali: New Test Environment.
Sonali: New test environment.
PAUL: But the kernel that you are using is myENV.
Sonali: No, it is new test ENV, no.
PAUL: But in the kernel, I can see in the top right-hand side, it's my ENV, it's written.
Sonali: This new test ENV. Where do I see my ENV?
PAUL: right-hand side, top.
PAUL: Where Google is written on top of that, just look.
PAUL: MyENB Python 3.13.9.
PAUL: Top, you just look into the top, huh? There, there, there, now you move the cursor.
PAUL: MyENVPython.
PAUL: Python, just wait, let me see, can I annotate or not?
PAUL: Annotate, whiteboard is there, direct annotation is not there here.
Rahul Parihar: Yep.
PAUL: Okay, can you see my NV? Right-hand side, top.
Hari Kumar: Is it my screen is sharing?
PAUL: Okay, okay, I think I'm looking into your screen, I got confused, sorry for that. Okay, first of all, OpenCMD, OpenCMD wants.
Sonali: Okay, I think my screen sharing is gone.
PAUL: No, no, no, your screen sharing is there. Fine, I was looking into Hari's screen, I got confused. Okay, now, just, first of all, open CMT, and stop using partial, because my test ENV, I can see 3.13.5 that you are using. Okay, fine. Alright.
PAUL: Okay, now, go inside this particular project folder.
PAUL: do a CD operation and go inside simple reaction, wherever you have kept it. Just quickly do a CM.
Sonali: Video operation on the side of it.
PAUL: Activate the environment.
PAUL: Okay? Now, in the, notebook, what was?
PAUL: Missing tel meter.
PAUL: Have you done requirement.txt?
Sonali: Now it's saying Langchen OpenAI not installed.
PAUL: That is fine, that is fine, leave that, because I know it is working, it's just that attribute is missing because of that. Have you taken the updated code that I have shared in GitHub? Yeah. You are using the old code.
Sonali: Second one is this.
Anshu singh: Beautiful.
PAUL: the updated code that I have shared in the.
Sonali: Second thing is this load.env was also not working.
Anshu singh: I'm deep on anything.
PAUL: Have you created .env file?
PAUL: Okay, I can see there is a .env file.
Sonali: Yeah, yeah, I have created it.
PAUL: Okay, this is the… Okay, first of all, see, do a collapse of that new test ENB. I don't want to see what is there. Directly, I want to look into that.
Anshu singh: Except for each of them.
PAUL: Okay, this is fine, this is fine. You have passed your OpenAI API key. Go back to the notebook.
PAUL: Okay, so here it's selling that, load.env. Scroll down, scroll down.
PAUL: Scroll down.
PAUL: Where have you done the import of that? That I want to check.
PAUL: Like, from .env, import load underscore dot env.
Sonali: That's where, like, this…
PAUL: One cell is missing. Okay, please look into the official code from our GitHub.
PAUL: look into, first of all, geta. Look into the code, okay? Because in your case, some cells are missing that, I feel.
PAUL: Please have a check. Because this is Python basic, this is nothing related to that.
PAUL: Okay, so please refer, and then get back to me.
PAUL: All right, next, Hari, you can start your screen sharing.
Sonali: Oh, hi.
Anshu singh: Hello?
Hari Kumar: So, yeah.
PAUL: Hari, start your screen sharing. Yes, anybody else who want to share their screen, let me know.
Kiran Rathod: Excellent.
Hari Kumar: Firstly, I would request, when we are executing these sales, maybe you go a little bit closer, because we could not be able to catch up. Maybe, myself, I could not be able to catch up.
Hari Kumar: While executing, at least when the dependencies are downloading the packages, right?
Hari Kumar: So…
PAUL: is the prerequisite of this course, FICAN.
PAUL: That's why I told in so many classes, before purchasing the course everywhere, basic prerequisite, we say Python.
Hari Kumar: Now, Python, definitely as we… we understand, but, while executing these, libraries, right, it is taking time, and then we're not able to catch up what we were talking. Maybe I'll try to rectify it from my side.
PAUL: See, if you could not catch up, really, I can say that. See, there is executing the sale. I have added so many print statements. It's not like I'm just…
PAUL: executing the exact code. That's the purpose of giving the print statement, so that you get it. If you… somewhere you see lag, it means that your Python is not good.
Hari Kumar: Sure, we'll improve on that.
Hari Kumar: One question from here. So, many a times I see, this is, it will be going on… I could not be able to stop it, actually. So, where exactly I can go and do it?
Hari Kumar: I understand from here, from this.
PAUL: There is an interrupt button, is there? No, on the top, interrupt. Yes, now interruption is done.
PAUL: Done, done, done.
Hari Kumar: You clicked on interrupt, yes.
PAUL: That is the interrupt button.
PAUL: Now, see, on the top, you will get, again, interrupt.
Hari Kumar: Yes. Yes, you can stop the interruption of a running scene.
Hari Kumar: Oop.
PAUL: Oh, see, these are basics.
Anshu singh: Hello?
Hari Kumar: I think, I think…
PAUL: And really, the idea is, see, before starting rank, it's not like that. That's why, like, before selling the course also, if you were in syllabus.
PAUL: Python is important, guys. Python, if you are not comfortable, it is going through a problem.
PAUL: Not now, at least, I can say in the next 1, 2, 3, because when I'll be discussing projects, things will be very, very complex, because I am not going to use Jupyter Notebooks.
Hari Kumar: Sure. Currently, if you see hostilities,
Hari Kumar: It is in progress. Maybe what is the reason here? Just wanted to understand.
PAUL: Execution, it's taking time in your system, that's why.
Hari Kumar: Okay.
PAUL: Oops.
PAUL: Generally, like, how do you do the execution? You don't use Shift-Enter?
Hari Kumar: No, I generally use this exclude cell, each cell.
PAUL: That's a bad practice.
Hari Kumar: Okay, U, SHIFT plus ENTER.
Hari Kumar: Okay.
PAUL: You have to close VSport again, and always do Shift plus Enter.
PAUL: Don't use buttons.
PAUL: Just try to open and check once more.
PAUL: then whoever Naga is.
Hari Kumar: And one question from my side, related to metadata.
Anshu singh: Thank you, the admin?
Hari Kumar: One small question from Maison related to metadata.
PAUL: Yes, Dan.
Hari Kumar: So, we are… it is the responsibility of the individual to send the metadata, I understand. So, how this metadata will be helpful in the, retrieval process, and
Hari Kumar: When we wanted to.
PAUL: It's not about only retrieval, a lot of filtering operations also that you can do.
Hari Kumar: Okay.
Hari Kumar: Maybe one or two examples are we covering in the upcoming sessions around these?
PAUL: Yes, those things will come. Like, when I'll be talking about a project, I'll be creating a detailed metadata of at least, I think, more than 50 to 20, 15 to 20 attributes.
Hari Kumar: This is the basics, guys, you have to understand. They…
PAUL: Two or three cannot expect me to teach everything in one shot.
PAUL: When we'll be working with much more?
PAUL: like, projects and concepts I'll be talking about. Metadata is very, very important. If you don't have a metadata, it becomes very, very hard, even to do your file updates at any point of time, if anything is changed, if you want to update it, how you'll do it.
Hari Kumar: Okay.
Anshu singh: It's been confused.
Hari Kumar: Yeah, got it. Shift-Enter, I'll do it, I'll proceed with that. Thank you.
PAUL: All very thuddy.
Anshu singh: Hello?
PAUL: Yes, yes. Who is this? Hello?
Anshu singh: Hello, sir?
PAUL: busy on.
Anshu singh: Sure.
PAUL: Anshuya, tell them.
Anshu singh: Yeah, sir, good afternoon.
PAUL: Hmm.
Anshu singh: So right now, I am, given the interview with two to three companies, okay? Nowadays, they ask me some basic questions.
Anshu singh: And I've given all the questions, but the result is negative. Why?
PAUL: I'll just write your pizza cannot respond.
Anshu singh: He did, start two to three days before I joined the interview of the under, and he asked me all the basic questions of the ride, okay? And asked me the question, like, give me all the details of Texas Blutter, which packages you are using this.
Anshu singh: Okay, and I will give him the answer, 223, just select Texas, bitter, all these things, okay?
Anshu singh: And you, right now, you are, asking me, like, at that, after a few classes, you can, wrote about the metadata. So, I can also explain the… about the metadata when we go for the retrieval part. In retrieval part, we can use the embeddings plus
Anshu singh: BM25 plus metadata also, right, sir?
PAUL: Correct. During the travel, if you are going with VM25, it means that…
Anshu singh: Yes, sir, I have, given all the answers related to this, okay? I, he told me that why you used BM25 is there, why you, for, embeddings, why you used this and that, or that time, I can give him all the answers, okay? Point-wise, okay? Then also asking that what is NCP, why we used, okay, how can we use, okay?
Anshu singh: And he gave me one architecture that is also available on the Cloudera, sorry.
Anshu singh: MCP, which companies are Anthropic.
PAUL: Alright.
Anshu singh: Yes, sir, but I can give an all-enco. In short time, the result is also negative Y.
Anshu singh: Some, male…
PAUL: Nobody can say, like, it totally depends upon your quality of responses.
PAUL: Like, if there are 3 candidates, if you answered all the questions, if there was another candidate who explained in a better way, I will go with him, it's not necessary. It totally depends upon the explanations.
PAUL: That little bit.
Anshu singh: Sir, the two… we are two… your two, two, three classes, which you are taught in, those also asked me that, in that interview, also.
PAUL: Why are you…
Anshu singh: Some basic level question, not given the… ask the… some unnecessary question. They give them the only basic questions.
Anshu singh: But also, I am not able to crack the interview.
PAUL: Really, like, it depends. Why you are getting a rejection, nobody can tell you. It totally depends upon the organization. If I'm in a bad mood, even a good candidate comes, I might reject it.
PAUL: So, like, a lot of things comes into the picture. It's not only that your technical knowledge, or somebody might be better, nobody can say, but the idea is that you have to keep on going.
Anshu singh: Hmm… Okay, thank you.
Salman Habeeb: This is Salman here.
PAUL: settlement.
Salman Habeeb: Which vector database can we use for enterprise-grade application? Is Koruma…
PAUL: more than 50.
PAUL: Chroma can also be used.
Salman Habeeb: Chroma can also be used, you know, from security point of view and from there.
PAUL: everything.
Salman Habeeb: And which one will you recommend? VV8, Pinecode?
PAUL: I use Pinecone.
Salman Habeeb: in production.
PAUL: I use Milverse in production, I use Viviate in production, I use Quadrant in production, so there is no recommendation.
Salman Habeeb: And they have on-prem.
PAUL: Component costing, budget, and clients… What they want.
Salman Habeeb: And these… they have on-premise version as well. Suppose I want to build an offline.
PAUL: Yeah, yeah, yeah. They have on-prem, it means that cloud-hosted clusters are there, dedicated clusters are there, shared clusters are there, totally. Like, what is your budget? It totally depends upon that.
Salman Habeeb: Okay, and let's say if I want to give role-based access.
Salman Habeeb: to my vector DB. So, are we going to.
PAUL: RDAC is… that is a feature of a database, it's not really a vector database.
Salman Habeeb: Yeah.
PAUL: Every database has an RBAC option.
Salman Habeeb: Let's say in my company, there are two levels of manager. Associate manager or a manager. So, associate manager should be able to look into the.
PAUL: Those are for enterprise-based solutions directly.
PAUL: You have to select your vector database, and for that, you have to look. I'm not going for a niche that only this vector divide that I am going to want. It's your one.
Salman Habeeb: about VectorDB? Based on role, a person should be able to fire a query, or give a query to RAG, based on the role, or RAG.
PAUL: 4K, alright, alright, alright. You are telling him that, okay. Then, see, only based on that, he can fire a query.
PAUL: No, that's the end of the…
Salman Habeeb: So even if he's able to fire a query, let's say my name is Salman, and I want to look into Paul's data. So even I want to say, okay, what is Paul's sales for this month? But my rag should not respond to that.
Salman Habeeb: So…
PAUL: That's what happens?
Salman Habeeb: Kind of a design dissection?
PAUL: This is much more about design stuff, because really, if you don't want to access your data, so let's take the example. One VectorDB has your own data, the other VectorDB has my data.
PAUL: Okay, so similarly, during the vector DB call, I will manage that for that specific user. I will create rule or something, some stuff that, if that user can only access that vector DB and not the other vector DBs.
Salman Habeeb: So, are we going to have this kind of functionality also in the project.
PAUL: This is decision logic, this is nothing related to AI.
PAUL: Just tell me, if there is an ifense case logic, is it related to building a rag or what?
Salman Habeeb: No, I'm just thinking, let's say, at DB level, can we limit it? You know, schema level.
PAUL: In BB level, there are a lot of operations that can be done, okay? Now, this is simple logic that I can build today only. Like, one retriever will be responsible for one type of person, the other retriever will be responsible for the other type of person. You just need to fire that…
Salman Habeeb: Turn it out at a retrieval level.
PAUL: Yes!
Salman Habeeb: Okay.
Salman Habeeb: Okay, and Paul, as we move ahead with the, you know, this bootcamp, are we going to have a design-level discussion as well at a system level?
PAUL: I'll be talking about one main design.
Salman Habeeb: Men does understand.
PAUL: Designs are not specific for everyone.
Salman Habeeb: Good night.
PAUL: It totally depends upon you, how you design, but I will be talking about a generic design. That I feel that, yes, it can be used everywhere, but at the end of the day, you have to understand, when we come to modular
PAUL: Right? Most of the components are plug-and-play. Which one you want, which one you… very specifically, like, it depends upon that business use case and other stuff.
PAUL: Okay, but I will give you a generic pipeline for ETL and other stuff, how to do that.
Salman Habeeb: But if I want to ask or have some design discussion with you, you're open.
PAUL: Okay, that you can share with me, there is no.
Salman Habeeb: That I can show. Okay. Thanks. Thanks, Chris.
minaal: That is it.
PAUL: Yes, anybody else who want to share this thing? Let me know in the chat as well.
Krishanu Santra: Sir, I… I wonder…
PAUL: one by one. First, I think Krishna, Santra is there. You go first.
Krishanu Santra: Okay, sir. So, the thing is, sir, my, OpenAI key is not working properly, I don't know why. Yesterday is working, but I shared my skin.
PAUL: Okay, Krishnau, I've added you. Naga, I've added you. Anybody else who want to share? Please let me know in the chat.
minaal: No.
Rahul Parihar: I would like.
PAUL: Menal want to share, okay, Menal…
Salman Habeeb: Sorry, Paul. Sorry, Paul, to interrupt. Just one more quick question. The rag, the simple rag that we ran today in Notebook, the output that was generated was abstractive, right? Abstractive and generative. It was not an extractive one.
Salman Habeeb: All the outputs which we're looking at.
PAUL: Generally, during the LLM generation, okay, you cannot directly say, most of the times, it will be abstractive only, it will never be extractive. Extractive is, it means that the exact piece of information, copy-paste, so that never happens again.
Salman Habeeb: Not even when the metadata or documents are returned.
PAUL: Yes, yes, then also, like…
PAUL: There will be some changes. Now, if you ask a very specific question, okay, now this and this exactly, tell me what is the info, then it can be, but not by default.
Naga: Hola, I have a question, Naga here.
Naga: So, I, my kernel is pointed to RAGNaga, but when I try to do CONDA here, it won't activate that.
Naga: I mean, it says Konda not recognized.
Naga: So, I… can you please help me?
PAUL: First, I am looking into Sonali's screen. Sonali, your issue solved.
PAUL: Planali.
Sonali: My issue's resolved.
PAUL: Then you can stop sharing, you know? Then you can stop.
Sonali: Yeah, my issue is resolved.
PAUL: Alright, alright, fine, I will move back to you. Alright. Hari is also done, Hari also, I will move back.
PAUL: Okay, now, coming to Krishnanu, your API issue, and Naga's some setup issue. Okay, Krishnau, your issue will be solved faster. Yes, tell me.
Krishanu Santra: Sir, the API is not working here, you can see that. I…
PAUL: Today's your first class?
Krishanu Santra: No, no, no, I'll… previously it is working, but I don't know how… why. Today I generated a new API key, and…
PAUL: Whenever you are telling me why, it means that there has to be a logic. So, first of all, tell me, where is the .env file?
Krishanu Santra: Okay.
PAUL: Where is the .env file? Again, these are Python basics.
Krishanu Santra: He… .
PAUL: Fix that name.env to .example, remove dot example. Man, these are Python basics, please go through Python.
Krishanu Santra: Okay, okay, listen.
PAUL: Yo… Alright, Krishnau, done. Okay, next I will come to Naga. Naga?
PAUL: Yes, your issue is with respect to?
Naga: She's a…
Nitesh: button.
Naga: I pointed my kernel to the… like, this.
PAUL: Okay, rag underscore, fine. 3.13, fine, yes.
Naga: thing, but, when I do Conda, it won't recognize it.
Naga: like, Conda, or Activate and the environment, right?
PAUL: system… see, your system is not recognizing Conda.
Naga: Mmm.
Naga: I mean, you have to…
PAUL: then you have to set the path in your environment variable according to your operating system. You have to look into, like, in which path Anaconda is there, and based on that, you have to set the path. Then, probably update, once the environment variables are updated, then it will be recognized.
Naga: And,
Naga: So, Paul, one question I have, the… I mean, this package that you gave today, is that different than the package you gave on the last week? Because this package has a simple rag, land chain, I think the other one don't have, right? All this? Is that right?
Naga: Or is it the same, both of them?
PAUL: Same, same, same.
Naga: Oh, it's all same load, okay.
Naga: Because I had, everything working in the last one, but again, I, using the GitHub, right, I, I downloaded, again, this package, okay? This one I, cloned.
PAUL: Okay.
Naga: So, what happened was… and then I think now suddenly this, stopped working. I don't know if I have to switch it back to the other one, maybe?
PAUL: You can try it, or you can change it. Right now, everything is in downloads, change your folder, do a clone, create the environment, and based on that, yes, you can do.
PAUL: Okay, anybody else who want to share, please let me know in the chat.
Nitesh: I think I've been waiting for a now. I mean, I don't.
PAUL: Okay, Nitesh, you want to share it?
Nitesh: No, I don't want to share, I have a.
PAUL: Okay, then go ahead with our question, Nitesh. Go ahead, go ahead, please.
Nitesh: Okay, so I was just going through the Jupyter Notebook, the local rag, Ulama, and was following up with you. I just wanted to understand, kind of a very quick, the flow. The reason what I'm asking is that I understood that we created a chunk, like the text splitter.
Nitesh: Right? And we… we chunk some of the 49, you know, 15 documents into the 49 chunks, and then we… when we do embedding, we are not passing those chunks for embedding, right? So it's like, moreover, we…
PAUL: Yes, really, have you looked into the code? I saw it so many times. Whenever we are calling the vector store, two things, we are passing the document, the embedding and the chunks.
PAUL: It means that you are not looking into the code.
Nitesh: No, I'm just saying, checking onto the create embedding part.
PAUL: CCC, create embedding, I'm just telling you once more. For example, let's take Ulama, okay? This one.
PAUL: Okay? Now, first of all.
PAUL: I'm… okay, so this is the part where we have done the chunking.
Nitesh: Yes?
Nitesh: Nope.
PAUL: Now, this is my embedding definition.
Nitesh: Yes.
PAUL: And this is my vector store when I'm doing the indexing. Can you see, yeah, chunks?
Nitesh: Yeah, here I can see, but I'm saying where embeddings, when we're doing embedding part, it's just a sample embedding we are doing, so I want a sample statement, so I was, like, confused.
PAUL: just for an example, no, I am only using this line. These lines are not required. I can delete it at any point of time. This is to show you that how embeddings look like, like the numbers, when I'm talking about floating point values.
Nitesh: Right, so, so when, when you go to, back to the, this, the next one, that we're storing to the vector database.
Nitesh: So, my understanding was that we… where we are giving this, which embedding has to use,
Nitesh: To store those chunks into the embeddings.
PAUL: Here, I'm passing, you know, from Chroma documents, here I am passing the chunks, and here I am passing which embeddings to be used.
Nitesh: And this embedding… that's… that's what I'm a little misunderstanding. This embedding is equal to embedding where this embedding is defined. I mean, is this a model.
PAUL: man, this CRM meeting is defined.
Nitesh: Wow.
PAUL: Really late.
Nitesh: Okay, okay, okay.
PAUL: That's why I'm telling it simple code. It's nothing that I have done any… it's simple, like, if you read the code step by step, you will understand it.
Nitesh: No, no, sorry, sorry.
PAUL: I hope you get it now.
Nitesh: Yeah, I got it. I was confused that when we are giving that model to embedding into the vector data store itself. Okay, sorry about that.
PAUL: It happens.
Nitesh: Yeah, thanks. Thanks, Paul. I think, this is my bad. And another follow-up question I had is that what I did is, meanwhile, I just tried to, I mean, deploy… deleted this doc slash ChromaDB. Just wanted to make sure that if I have already had, if I have to re-execute the vector store creation.
Nitesh: if I delete that particular directory, it should…
PAUL: Again, you have to do the embedding and other stuff. You cannot do anything. If that directory is deleted, nothing can be done.
Nitesh: Yeah, but there's a score we can re-create, right?
PAUL: Yes, you can always recreate. By executing the same cell, the recreation happens, no. But if you delete this ChromaTV folder, it means it's gone, and you have to do the embedding again.
Nitesh: Right, and that's what I tried. Yeah, but I had… when I tried the same thing after deleting this, it just did not allow me, with the same name, I have to do a Droba Cream 1, DEV1, might be putting some traces, or thus left some tresses, which is not allowing me to do the same.
PAUL: I think it can, because, see, generally, like, I know that if you delete this file again with the same, it should create. That's the logic. So, if you have deleted, and again, if you rerun the cell, it should be… it can be created with the same name. There should not be any issues in that.
Nitesh: Okay, I mean, I'll check later on, that's not a problem. Thanks, thanks, Nepal, that's what I had.
minaal: Hi, Paul, penalty.
PAUL: Yeah, I'm in the tech.
minaal: Paul, while the session, by 11am, I was able to… I was working on the VS Code, and I was able to execute the code. But, however, after some time, I mean, right now, I'm not able to open VS Code itself.
minaal: So…
PAUL: Dr.
PAUL: I mean, I'll just wait, I will add you to panelists. Are you in panelist, Meena?
minaal: Yeah, yeah, I'm already there, should I share my screen?
PAUL: Here you go ahead and share your screen.
PAUL: Oh…
minaal: I hope the screen is visible.
PAUL: Yes, it is visible, girl.
minaal: Yeah, so… so here is my VS Code.
minaal: So if I… even if I double-click, it is… I'm unable to open it, so I was just wondering if it is the task manager, or due to some CPU usage or memory usage.
minaal: But, meaning…
PAUL: In the meantime, what you can do, see, if AJ…
PAUL: install 2 or 3 other code editors, like I was using anti-gravity, wind stop, cursor, just install. If one doesn't work, start working on another.
PAUL: Because really, like, this is an OS-level issue.
minaal: Oh, yeah, yeah, I agree.
PAUL: So, like, that's the best thing. I have more than 6 to 7 editors. I keep on switching from 1 to 1. Okay, so at least keep 2 or 3. I think it will be better.
minaal: Okay, okay, no worries. And, one last…
PAUL: Even if you don't have the S code, then also you can exclude everything from the terminal.
minaal: Okay, from CMD, you mean?
PAUL: Yes, from CMD, everything you want.
minaal: Yep, right. Yeah.
PAUL: wood.
minaal: Yeah, one last query. So, Paul, I have only 8GB RAM in my local, so whatever we did today using the Docker and Ollama, same thing, I mean, since my local is not that capable, so I can use only the OpenAI
minaal: With the paid one itself, right?
PAUL: Use Gemini, no. Don't… see, when I use OpenAI, I think Gemini, majorly, I think, for today's class, whatever we have done, it could be done.
PAUL: And in free. So, OpenAI is paid. So, like, if you feel that in some case where your Gemini resource is exhausted, then switch to OpenAI. Otherwise, keep on using Gemini. The idea is that there is a daily limit. You hit the daily limit, and after that, if you feel, move to that.
minaal: Okay, cool, sounds good.
Rahul Parihar: ain't.
PAUL: Because there is even a Grok LLM, but again, emitting is not there. Like, tomorrow, little bit about Grok also, I will tell you if a few people might not know about it. There are also free models which are hosted.
minaal: Yep. Paul, can I share my screen?
PAUL: Yes, just wait, let me adminal to attendees. Yes, next you want to share?
PAUL: mine.
PAUL: Round, round, round, okay.
PAUL: Love it.
PAUL: Okay, now you can stop sharing, and you can do it on your own, no.
Naga: No, I'm like, I'm still responsive.
Naga: Okay, yeah, I think iPhone.
PAUL: Okay, next we want to share, like, Swagoth.
Kiran Rathod: Take care.
PAUL: Minu, Share, Esi, Nitesh already done, I think.
Kiran Rathod: I wanted to share.
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: Paul, I wanted to also share.
PAUL: Who Srinivas.
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: Continuous, yeah.
PAUL: Honestly.
Meenu: I have… I have one question.
PAUL: Yes, Minu, please go ahead with your question.
Meenu: Paul, there is one property in which, like, for, while creating the vector DB, vector store variable, you pass one variable, that is the persist. So, what is that? Can you please…
PAUL: It's a persistent directory. It means that in your local machine, a directory will be created. Persistent means permanent. It means that that is available permanent in your local, so that is basically that command.
Meenu: So, if we don't set this property, it will be on fly.
PAUL: Yes, on the app. Yes, yes, yes.
Meenu: Okay.
Meenu: Thank you.
PAUL: Moved on next. I don't want to ask a question.
PAUL: Yes, Kiran, question, or you want to share your screen?
Kiran Rathod: Oh, did you have Ms.
PAUL: Okay, Kira, normal writer, I will add you.
PAUL: Okay, run, done.
PAUL: Duablatiko… Rohitly bathtub… Okay, quickly, I'm just unmuting everyone.
PAUL: Yes. Now I'm looking into Rahul Parihar's screen. Yes, Rahul, thank you.
Rahul Parihar: So, Paul, thanks. So one issue is, you know, I'm just getting my cash is getting stuck here.
Rahul Parihar: And in the… in the… in the UV, connection.
Rahul Parihar: it is… when I'm running, my .environment is loaded. I have my configuration files with all the keys and stuff like that.
Rahul Parihar: But what I'm trying to face problem over here is,
Rahul Parihar: is that, I don't know why it is asking for…
Rahul Parihar: Why it's complaining about all the…
PAUL: It's not…
Rahul Parihar: Back in Leon.
PAUL: It means that some issues are there that you need to debug.
Rahul Parihar: But how do…
PAUL: right now, tell me, what is the issue? It means that, tell me, what is the issue that you are facing?
Rahul Parihar: Issue is, this is getting loaded, but, you know, the Langchen module is not getting found. However, in the…
PAUL: This is your VNB, okay? First of all, open your terminal, activate the environment, and open the Python shell.
PAUL: Always use CMD? Okay, you are on Mac, I think, no? No issues, fine, great.
PAUL: Right now you are in simple rack chain base, deactivate this, stuff, because your virtual environment name was .vnv, so activate…
PAUL: Okay, if it's not there, then activate VNB first.
Rahul Parihar: Activate… Yeah, not VIN.
PAUL: But why? Because you are using…
PAUL: Alright, because right now, I know that your .VNV is activated. Fine, yes. This base is coming, I think you have gone down your system, fine. Now…
PAUL: pip, install IFN RTS.
PAUL: Do you have UV in your system?
Rahul Parihar: Yeah, I do have UV in the system, and I tried with UV.
PAUL: Wait, wait, wait. First of all, let's look into the terminal of BS Code, then I will come back here.
Rahul Parihar: It gets stuck in the cache, and it takes a very long time to not…
Rahul Parihar: get fully completed. It's just take a pretty long time.
Rahul Parihar: I've tried to…
PAUL: Yeah, okay, okay, okay, okay. Just do one thing. First of all, delete both of those photos.v8bv and VN.
PAUL: Then, again, you have .idea, you have opened this in PyCharm also.
Rahul Parihar: Yeah, I was just trying a different IDE.
PAUL: It's not about IDs. You don't need ID. Without ID, everything, you can do it.
PAUL: I don't know, like, ID is not important.
PAUL: Without VSport, I can do the entire stuff.
PAUL: Delete.vnv and . Both those VNVs, delete it.
Rahul Parihar: Deleted.
PAUL: Yes, delete. Complete delete.
PAUL: Move to trash here. Then the first one also.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Where is your .env file?
Rahul Parihar: env example, you know?
PAUL: I share.env, it has to be .env when you execute it. Most of you are using .env.example.
PAUL: It has to be always .env, I share. What should be the format of .env with you?
PAUL: Using a dot EM logo.
Rahul Parihar: The admin documentation says .env, I just copied this .env.example over here in.
PAUL: Once you execute that file, a new file will be created, no .env.
Rahul Parihar: I'm a…
PAUL: And paste it.
PAUL: Because once you execute this, that's why I shared that particular command. Close this for a minute, we have deleted. Delete. Just delete stuff here.
PAUL: Yeah, close, close, close. Okay? And just, go back to your, wrap.
PAUL: close this VS Code, I don't need VS Code.
PAUL: Close VS code.
PAUL: Close this all… Close everything.
Rahul Parihar: Okay.
PAUL: Close everything.
PAUL: You are switching between ideas, but really it is not important, okay? Now, make it full screen.
PAUL: I don't want any other stuff. Just increase the font, Command plus plus.
PAUL: Command++.
PAUL: Okay?
Rahul Parihar: You know.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Not much as I can do.
PAUL: Alright, close this tab, open a new tab.
PAUL: First of all, open a tab, open a tab, otherwise you will lose that. Now, close the other tab.
PAUL: Right? Don't click in, don't click anywhere.
Rahul Parihar: Okay.
PAUL: Okay? Alright.
PAUL: Now, first of all, create an environment using UB, let's see. UVNV.vnv.
PAUL: This is all Python stuff now.
PAUL: dot VNVVVV, V-E-N-V.
PAUL: Before that also, before that, VNEV is the package which UV will be using.
PAUL: You just remember this command, don't… Always look into the history.
PAUL: UVVNV.
PAUL: dot VNB. Yes. Just add that V, you are missing that V in the second word.
PAUL: V, add a V.
Rahul Parihar: Double V, you mean to say dot V.
PAUL: Matt, see, ENV is written, right there, V before ENV.
PAUL: UV, after that, only ENV is written, it has to be V.
PAUL: VNV.
PAUL: Yes, now it entered.
PAUL: Okay? Now activate the environment. The command is given, just press the right arrow key, done. Now do UVP install, or press the right arrow key automatically before that add UV.
PAUL: This is all Python.
PAUL: Okay, now see, it's telling that you require a CPython 3.3, but you have only the wills for tors. Now, it's very specifically telling you to downgrade, based on the error that we can see.
PAUL: Okay, so based on this particular error, what you can say, delete the current environment to write deactivate.
PAUL: Okay? And, create a new environment with the Python version, probably 3.11 or 3.12, just right.
PAUL: Because in your system, whichever is available, I don't know that. But.
Rahul Parihar: So I was flying with 3.11, you know?
PAUL: Okay, go ahead with 3-dotel.
PAUL: Already exists, it's telling, please delete the… no, no, no, no, no, I don't want confusions. First of all, delete. Write rm space hyphen RF.
PAUL: and .VNVR, delete.
PAUL: They can run the command.
PAUL: Again, just run the command for a confirmation.
PAUL: Okay, now activated.
PAUL: Let's see now.
PAUL: You are on Mac? Which M1, M2, M3?
Rahul Parihar: M1…
PAUL: M1, it will work.
PAUL: Okay, now the same UVAP install, let's see what happens.
PAUL: Everything got installed? Great.
Rahul Parihar: So, one of the things is,
Rahul Parihar: The Langken version is not one, it is, it is installing this version, 0.3.
PAUL: Just a straight line, no? Upgrade lampshin. Do a, upgrade lan chain.
Rahul Parihar: UV, PIP.
Rahul Parihar: install lanking.
PAUL: Upgrade language, and if I knew before that, these are basic Python commands.
PAUL: That's why Python stuff, most of you are getting stuck at Python.
PAUL: Hyphen capital L.
PAUL: Don't write full upgrade, just write the capital one, okay?
PAUL: Okay, you have done with that. Okay, fine. Similarly, just upgrade the other package, whichever you feel.
Rahul Parihar: The core is updated, right? This is… this is upgraded, this is upgraded.
PAUL: So now I should be able to…
Rahul Parihar: Now I should be able to do it, right?
PAUL: Yeah.
PAUL: I hope so, just try…
PAUL: at least check the import section, just on the first part, okay? Now, if I'm talking about, again, don't open…
PAUL: Directly, like, without this, also, you can directly switch to… The ideas.
Rahul Parihar: I hope you.
PAUL: You have done, sh… Show me your, requirement.txt3. What are the contains? Do a cat?
PAUL: CAT?
PAUL: And then requirement.txt, yes.
PAUL: Okay, in Kat and Jupiter… okay. So, just right here… Jupiter, and hit enter.
PAUL: Shop it now, and hit enter.
PAUL: Okay, I think hyphen lab is not there, hyphen notebook, just add that hyphen, hyphen notebook.
PAUL: Hyphen, hyphen, add hyphen.
PAUL: If you don't add an hyphen, it always switches to some other environment.
PAUL: Okay, and now execute.
PAUL: First, only the import section, just… yeah.
PAUL: Shift-Enter, Shift-Enter, Shift-Enter.
PAUL: Hmm.
PAUL: Got the problem.
PAUL: See, you executed what is the Python version initially?
Rahul Parihar: 314.
PAUL: So what I told, write Jupyter hyphen notebook. And you wrote again, Jupyter space notebook. I repeat it more than 4 times.
Swagatika: Boom!
PAUL: These are all Python basics, man. In data science class, when you start data science, then we teach these type of things. Hyphen, add an hyphen.
PAUL: If you don't have an iPhone, it won't be recovered.
Rahul Parihar: What is hyphen means, you know? Can you, can you just say?
PAUL: Jupyter's base notebook is the global package. Jupyter hyphen Notebook refers to the current environment notebook.
Rahul Parihar: But why can't I open in WinServe or Visual Studio, you're demoing and everything, and so why can't I just open in.
PAUL: You can open here also.
PAUL: You have to be good with the ideas.
PAUL: If you, like, say, you are switching multiple IDs, then also you are not getting the result. I'm telling that without using IDs, also you can do. IDs make your life easier. Otherwise, everything can be done from the terminal.
Rahul Parihar: Okay, okay, I see your point.
Rahul Parihar: I just will try, I don't.
PAUL: But terminal guy, rather than using EY always, that's fine.
Rahul Parihar: So, I, I select here, environment, the same environment, 313.
Rahul Parihar: Or…
PAUL: the name that you have created.vn, we select that.
PAUL: Why you were writing Conda and other stuff? You created using UV? No, who is sharing? I am looking into some other screen, just wait.
PAUL: Yes.
PAUL: Yeah, and just take a look at this.
Swagatika: Extreme,
PAUL: Just be on mute for now, Suvati.
PAUL: imported.
Rahul Parihar: Excuse me.
PAUL: Correct environment, it's working, it's working.
PAUL: It's working.
PAUL: Rahul, let's… Hello, sir.
PAUL: Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Rahul Parihar: I'll try and fix this. I'll try and fix this OpenAPI issue, yeah, thanks.
PAUL: Just create a .env file, that's the only thing.
PAUL: Or a rename that .env example to, .env.example to .env.
PAUL: Okay? You are done.
Rahul Parihar: Okay. Dot. Okay.
PAUL: Alright, next, Kieran, we go ahead.
Kiran Rathod: This particular, code is… I'm facing this issue here in this part.
PAUL: Okay, now see, this is an older input, no? Just add from Langchen underscore, community.
Kiran Rathod: You can score quicker.
PAUL: underscore community, okay? Jesse, now, Rita.
Kiran Rathod: That didn't miss your billet, yeah.
Kiran Rathod: And I wanted to know if, like, for when we're running ULAMA locally, right? It has to be up and running always throughout the process that we are running our code?
PAUL: just be sure Ollama is running. You don't need to run the model, just Olama should be running in your luggage.
Kiran Rathod: In the beginning of the notebook, right, there was one ULAMA poll we had returned the code. So, what is the difference between pull that we're doing here, and what is the run we're doing on the local?
PAUL: Pull, only download the image.
PAUL: Run means download plus run the mode.
Kiran Rathod: So it's always run, I'll have to use in the command prompt to make it up and running?
PAUL: If you want to talk with the model, then use run. I never talk, so I don't use run, I only use full.
Kiran Rathod: Okay.
Kiran Rathod: It would be a one-time activity, right? Once we do it, do a poll, it should be okay. Okay.
PAUL: Yes.
PAUL: Alright.
Kiran Rathod: Yeah.
AC: Hey, hey, Paul.
AC: Hello, sir.
PAUL: So I've got… yes, you go ahead, I think.
PAUL: Jovatika is there. You want to share, I think?
Swagatika: No, no, sir, so just a simple question.
PAUL: Okay, just wait, I have added you to panelists. Amit?
shrey: I need to…
PAUL: Amin, you want to share? Who want to share? Shrey?
shrey: Yes, sir.
PAUL: Shrey, add to panelists, okay. Amit, you want to share?
Amit Singh: Paul said, I'm trying on my own as of now, I'm trying to run.
PAUL: Okay, so you try? At the end, let me know.
Amit Singh: Yep, yep.
PAUL: Then, Paran… Paran Dama no.
PAUL: Paran Dharma, yes, I think, you need.
Parandhama: Hi, Paul.
PAUL: Yes.
Parandhama: Paul, actually, by using the comparing OLAMA and the embeddings model, Gemma model, I can be able to execute the complete notebook. Okay.
Parandhama: But going for… going forward for the upcoming notebooks, is there a specific,
Parandhama: code snippet is required to use every header, or Volama-based, or is it work compatible with the existing code? Whatever you're providing?
PAUL: It will be working with the existing codebook for the other notebooks.
PAUL: I won't be using OLAM, I think majorly I'll be switching to OpenAI or Gemini.
PAUL: If you want, you can do the configuration for Rolamine by doing an edit.
Parandhama: Okay, individual notebook, while executing, all of my compatible code I need to fix for the… correct?
PAUL: Yes, if you want to use Olama, you have to do the changes by yourself.
Parandhama: Sure, pop it.
Parandhama: Agreed. Thank you.
PAUL: Rohit Srivastav, and then finally coming to Jagapati.
PAUL: Yes, please.
Rohit Srivastava: It has… Hello, sir. Hey, hi, sir, aren't you?
PAUL: We have the first row is 14 gold.
Rohit Srivastava: Yeah, hey, hi, Savangshu. I mean, this is my first, appearance here. I had…
Rohit Srivastava: I mean, I joined only on Thursday. But that said, I did went through your previous, recordings, and
Rohit Srivastava: Those research papers which you mentioned and discussed in your previous classes, they were really interesting, and I would love to add the link to them.
Rohit Srivastava: That's.
PAUL: It's available, everything is available in Notion.
Rohit Srivastava: No, it's not available, it's not showing me. That's the reason why I'm asking you.
PAUL: Just wait. It is not possible, like, I update you.
Rohit Srivastava: I agree.
PAUL: morning before class. See?
Rohit Srivastava: Honestly, I mean, in this.
PAUL: This is your… this is your post-motion, okay?
Rohit Srivastava: Yeah, yeah?
PAUL: Wait a minute.
Rohit Srivastava: Wait a minute, wait a minute, wait a minute, wait a minute, wait a minute, hold on.
Rohit Srivastava: Can I share my screen?
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: ingested.
PAUL: Yeah. I will add you to panelist, you can share.
PAUL: Going to punished.
PAUL: Anybody from panelists, Cherie and others? I think Swagothika, also your question was… one question. Just wait, Swagothika, after this, you go ahead, Chris.
PAUL: Yeah, so…
Rohit Srivastava: Alright, desktop 2, alright.
PAUL: Awesome.
Rohit Srivastava: Oh, man, this… Just give me a sec.
PAUL: Green color button will be there, please.
Rohit Srivastava: No, no, no, no, that's not a problem.
Rohit Srivastava: This is the max security part.
PAUL: Okay, first time, if you're screen sharing, that pop-up comes. System.
Jagapathi: Paul, meanwhile, simple question.
PAUL: Yeah, go ahead.
Jagapathi: So you… the local one you showed, right? So, you just pull the…
Jagapathi: Embed models and run it, or just show in the…
Jagapathi: I mean, to have the data retrieved from the local models should run it right.
PAUL: You don't need to run automatically Landshain, like, the integration of Ulama is in such a way that automatically, we know that if the model is available, LanChain can make the call. You don't need to run the model or anything.
Rohit Srivastava: But anyways.
Jagapathi: Oh, okay, thank you.
Rohit Srivastava: Hey, I'm sorry, am I audible?
PAUL: Yes, yes.
Rohit Srivastava: Yeah, so the first time, this, like, this is a pain, what I get. Alright, just give me a second, let me open that,
Rohit Srivastava: Yeah. Here is what I see.
Rohit Srivastava: And let me put it, like, share, alright, share this.
Rohit Srivastava: Can you see my screen?
PAUL: Yes, I can see your screen.
Rohit Srivastava: Yeah, so this is what I get. I mean, this is a link which you provided, and I opened that link.
PAUL: top.
PAUL: right corner, there is something written as Ultimate Rack Course. Click on it.
Rohit Srivastava: Left corner, rather. Okay, yeah.
Rohit Srivastava: Okay.
PAUL: All the class content is available here.
Rohit Srivastava: Awesome. Thank you so much. That's question number one. Number two is,
Rohit Srivastava: Thank you. Thank you, Saranchu. The other thing is,
Rohit Srivastava: when we are doing, like, so what I've seen, the first of the RAG, again, bootcamp order from Krish, and what we were discussing up until now also.
Rohit Srivastava: We are loading all the documents together, and there was an option of a lazy load.
Rohit Srivastava: My challenge is that I'm… I'm trying to manage data of an enterprise which has billions of files and petabytes of storage.
PAUL: Alright, fine.
Rohit Srivastava: So, in this case, what approach would you provide? I mean, like, a parallel embedding, or…
Rohit Srivastava: I mean, lazy load, of course, that has to be there, but parallel embedding?
PAUL: It's not… then I only be using Langchen only, you know?
Rohit Srivastava: Okay, okay, okay.
Rohit Srivastava: Yeah, I just wanted to get your feel.
PAUL: And see, if actually I'm, doing it in huge scale, I'll be moving to other sources, like unstructured, vectorized, those are actually used in production.
PAUL: Okay, when…
Rohit Srivastava: Typically, I don't use… yeah, typically, I don't use Python for my enterprise applications. I…
Rohit Srivastava: I very conveniently switched to Go.
PAUL: Who is… yes.
PAUL: That's the correct decision also. Even I don't like Python. Python is a very slow…
Rohit Srivastava: It, it sucks.
PAUL: I prefer Rust. Okay, Rust or Google? No, Rust, I haven't graduated to Rust yet.
Rohit Srivastava: I haven't graduated Rust. I… all my life, I had been a C programmer. I've worked predominantly in the kernel space.
Rohit Srivastava: So I, I just graduated to… Goal.
PAUL: Okay, very specifically, like, ANCO also, if I… there are few… what happens generally in the data science world, there are few things that cannot be done. It means that, if I want something with respect to deep learning and other stuff, directly I can use Torch. Torch is available on C++.
PAUL: I switched to that particular version, and I do most of the tasks, okay? Similarly, now some recent libraries are coming with C++,
PAUL: rough support. There is support for NPM also, but I use less that. Okay, so in your case, if I'm…
PAUL: in your case of loading petabytes of data, like, my go-to will be something like using C++, Go, okay, something like that that I will be using for sure.
Rohit Srivastava: But Rust is… Rust is an environment which you are recommending, I can sense that.
PAUL: Rust is another programming language. Right now, a lot of libraries are coming.
PAUL: is first written on Rust, then a Python wrapper has been built on top of that.
Rohit Srivastava: Okay, okay. So, yeah, so that's separate. The third thing is choosing the vector database. I mean.
Rohit Srivastava: primarily from a scaling perspective, and the magnitude of, the amount of data what I need to handle, I think Milverse serves the purpose.
PAUL: I mean, Melvis is, like, I use it for, like, billions of embeddings.
PAUL: Yeah, exactly. Actually, when you talk with the Milverse team, they give you a good deal also, because I know in Singapore, those guys. Okay, like, really, like, Milverse, I prefer it. But again, like, getting a dedicated cluster can be costly sometimes.
Rohit Srivastava: No, my market segment is not cost-oriented, to be honest.
PAUL: Now, if it is much.
Rohit Srivastava: Yup.
PAUL: But then, typically, you can select.
PAUL: I want a solution?
Rohit Srivastava: Yeah, they want a solution which… which, serves their purpose, and efficiently serves their purpose, by… while maintaining their privacy and, all other security, you know,
PAUL: tick.
Rohit Srivastava: box.
PAUL: See, like, using a pre-hosted cluster, because at the end of the day, Milbus also uses the same thing, AWS, GCP, and Azure.
Rohit Srivastava: No, Zillow.
Rohit Srivastava: Zillas is the cloud instance. We can post Midwest On-prem also.
PAUL: Yes, now, on Zillis, they use the same cloud, AWS… Yeah, I know, I know.
Rohit Srivastava: I don't… that's… that's the reason why I was saying I'm only talking about Milvas.
PAUL: Okay. Melverse is good, like, I love Melverse, but I feel that I create my own cluster and host it in Melbours, rather than directly taking everything from them.
Rohit Srivastava: Okay, okay.
PAUL: I prefer building my own EKS cluster, and inside that EKS cluster, I'll be hosting the Milba spots.
Rohit Srivastava: Oh, okay, okay, okay, okay, okay, okay. So that's one, one approach which I'm, which, I can, I can think of.
PAUL: Yes, like, if you… because that is a little bit headache of doing that setup and other stuff, if… directly, if you can take it, it's good.
Rohit Srivastava: No, typically, yeah, typically because I'm dealing with financial institutions, and they're… they're really, really hesitant to go on cloud.
PAUL: Then on-prem also, you can do it, on a bare-metal server.
PAUL: That is also possible.
Rohit Srivastava: Yes.
Rohit Srivastava: Yes, and… Mmm, the third…
Rohit Srivastava: I think I forgot, sorry. I mean, age is not on my side, I guess. Thank you. Thank you so much.
PAUL: Okay, alrighty. If anything is there, you can always drop me a link.
shrey: Circulation, huh?
Naga: Hi, everyone, Naga here.
Swagatika: Hello?
PAUL: Okay, first, Swagar Tika. Then, Naga, yes, I'm looking into your screen.
Naga: So, this is continuously running and not installing. I mean, it looks like it's doing something, but I don't know, it's almost 10 minutes, it's sitting here.
PAUL: This is an environment level issue. It means that… I don't know why it is getting stuck. It means that some type of execution, check installed packages…
PAUL: So it's clear, it's telling something is satisfied here, continuously, and… Okay, fine. Stop that execution. Stop that execution, click on the interrupt button on top.
PAUL: interrupt, interrupt. Yes, from there also you can do, or in the top, however way you want to. Just stop the…
PAUL: This is just a verification.
Naga: This interpreter… go to…
PAUL: This is that square boss, square boss.
Naga: Okay, interpret, okay, okay.
PAUL: Yeah.
Naga: Huh.
PAUL: Okay? Just wait.
PAUL: After interrupting, yeah, just wait a few seconds, that might take. Yeah, Swahatika, in the meantime, you can go ahead.
PAUL: Sray, I think you also want to share your screen. Yes, sir. Shall I, shall I share? Start sharing.
shrey: Okay.
PAUL: Quality card in there.
shrey: Okay, is my screen visible?
PAUL: Especially your screen is visible.
shrey: Okay, so I have a very basic,
shrey: Question with respect to this VS code. Actually, I'm trying to, set up the VNV. Okay, the VNV is already set up.
shrey: And, but somehow, whenever I try to configure the interpreter, I'm getting an issue.
shrey: I've been using, this… this is a kid.
shrey: So if I select… Select the interpreter.
shrey: So, by default, I'm, like, I'm trying to use CVNV, right?
shrey: I… I selected this…
PAUL: Selected.
shrey: post this.
shrey: I'll post this when I try to execute, I get this error.
PAUL: Okay, fine, in the terminal, in the terminal, just open Python.
PAUL: Open Python.
PAUL: Okay, and copy-paste that link from LangChanolama import.com.
PAUL: Happy Wednesday!
shrey: I actually, I created a test file for that, just the same thing.
PAUL: Okay, fine, okay, a Python script, alright, fine.
shrey: Yeah, I created a test Python file, and then I executed test.py. Okay.
PAUL: Apart from here, first do an exit, exit, first do an exit, or, I think, control that in…
PAUL: Windows here.
shrey: One more control that…
PAUL: That was required, yes. Now, execute this.
shrey: of that.
shrey: Yeah, actually, I tested it. It's running fine. I wasn't having any import issue. But somehow, with respect to VS Code, I'm unable to…
PAUL: Till now, it is just wait. Let the execution be finished.
shrey: Sure, sure.
Naga: It is still, running the interrupting kernel problem.
PAUL: Just a time.
PAUL: The execution would slink some time.
shrey: I don't know why this is taking this much of time.
PAUL: Scale VS code.
Naga: Killa VSC.
PAUL: ways go down.
Naga: Okay, I'll close it and open it.
PAUL: I don't know why this is happening. Last time, also, in your case, it got stuck.
Naga: Again, I'm opening.
PAUL: Okay.
Naga: I set the environment variable also, and the path.
PAUL: Now Conda is getting recognized?
Naga: Yeah, yeah, conda is getting recognized, path is getting recognized, no problem. So, I am currently at the Langshan, okay? So, I will again activate the conda.
PAUL: Just wait, just wait, just wait.
PAUL: Okay, you were working with Conda.
Naga: Yeah.
PAUL: Okay, fine. Activate the Quanda environment. And, don't use VSport this time. Switch to Jupyter for now. Okay? Let's see what happens.
Naga: Ho ho.
PAUL: 8.
Naga: it's simple reaction, okay. Switch to Jupyter? What… how do I do?
PAUL: First of all, kill VSport. Kill it.
Naga: Okay, yes, for… okay, yes, yes.
PAUL: Okay, now go back to your, terminal, close this command prompt, the other one, where simple rack chain was written, open that command prompt.
Naga: Oh, command, you want to go to command prompt?
PAUL: Yes, open command prompt and go to that simple rag chain.
Naga: Oh, God.
PAUL: and…
Naga: Okay.
Naga: Right-click, Okano's Administrator.
PAUL: Anybody else who want to share their screen? Because right now.
Swagatika: Hello, sir, I have a question, sir.
PAUL: Yes, please go ahead. I was waiting for it.
Swagatika: Sir, if I have a folder.
PAUL: unfortunate.
Swagatika: contains multiple types of files, like some HTML, some PDF, or some text file, or some images.
Swagatika: So, how can it read the files at the same time?
PAUL: You want to read all the files in one shot.
Swagatika: Yes.
PAUL: into a star.star, it means that everything within that folder, that can be picked up.
Swagatika: with this, file PDF, library, I can read, all this file at a time, like, if images are there.
PAUL: That's not PyPDF. PyPDF will only help you to read the PDF. But, you are talking about different file formats within a folder. So, for reading different file formats, you need to have your different type of loaders.
PAUL: I'm talking about reading those files. So, similarly, like, before, initializing, like, for every file type, you have initialized the loader. Okay, before that,
PAUL: when you are actually loading that document. During that time, you can have a simple logic, like star, dot, for this particular type of loader for this file. So, you have to just separate the logic based on the different type of file types that you…
Swagatika: Okay.
shrey: Okay, I guess, after restarting…
Naga: We're gonna…
PAUL: After restarting, it's working.
shrey: Yes, sir. See, I gotta…
PAUL: Yeah, okay, okay, fine. It happens sometimes.
Naga: Paul, I made the comment prompt?
shrey: Chef?
shrey: And I'm just stop it.
Naga: I'm the…
PAUL: Alright, Shrey, I think it is done then, yeah.
Naga: Well…
PAUL: Change it all trays, done.
AC: Hey, I have a question.
PAUL: And it will start sharing.
PAUL: Who has a question?
AC: I have a question, Paul.
PAUL: Estein Alright, ACOID.
AC: Yeah. So, again, right, I don't know what the next step, next, like.
AC: Sessions are going to be, like, are we going to have a detailed session on document loaders, text splitters, embedding?
PAUL: Not in the future, no. Now, everything in day one, how can I complete my.
AC: No, no, no, no, I'm not… you don't have to… I understand that, you don't have to explain anymore. The other thing is, I wanted to do some research. Now, my use case is, like, I'm trying to scrape websites, right? So, is there a package that I'm… so I use Beautiful Soup for…
PAUL: No, that is really bad. LLM-based scrappers are there, but it's somehow… the cost can be increasing. Like, it totally depends upon the type, like, the different types of websites, whether it's the same website you scrap at different time, or whether it's totally different website.
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: away. Okay.
AC: So, so my point is, my question is, like, there is… you would know, right, for every website that I'm trying to scrap, every website has a robot.txt58, robots.txt5.
PAUL: Yes, yes.
AC: Is there… is there a package that I can experiment with which will comply with that robots.tx? I don't want to do, like, call that web… call that endpoint
AC: and then get the… get the contents in a list, and I don't want to do that. I want to use a package which will automatically comply with the robots.txt, so…
PAUL: In reality, there is no every time you have to do a configuration for that.
PAUL: you can do it using Fire Crawl, and then you have your, Crawl4AI. These two are the libraries.
AC: File crawl and crawl for AI, okay.
PAUL: Yes.
Naga: These are the ones that you're…
PAUL: Yeah, Naga, wait first. Yes, AC. These are the two libraries using which.
AC: that I can, like, experiment with.
PAUL: Yes.
AC: Okay.
PAUL: Like, even there, right now, to the current website, there is LLMs.com.
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: Perfect spot.
PAUL: If you have seen it.
PAUL: Okay, so that can also be ended.
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: Yeah, that.
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: Alright, thanks.
Naga: There we go!
PAUL: Send me this, please be on mute.
PAUL: Yeah, if not, tell me now.
Naga: Yeah, yeah, I'm at the, this song.
PAUL: Okay, now, so activate the environment that you have.
Naga: Conda… using the conduct activator?
PAUL: However you created, I don't know that. However you created…
PAUL: just activate that particular command. Now you are creating again. I'm asking you to activate.
Naga: Activate, okay, sorry, 7.
PAUL: Okay, Srinivas, in the meantime, you can also start your screen sharing.
PAUL: Yeah, that's.
Naga: Paul, it's activated.
PAUL: Alright. Now, Just do that, pip list.
Naga: Please fuck it.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Why it's showing blank?
Naga: It's not present, I think.
PAUL: Okay, fine. Just to do a pip show space launching.
Naga: Yeah, it's… It's in the…
PAUL: First of all, like, there is some issue, I feel. Because if you do a paper list, it should show you the packages. Why it's showing script file D… really, like, D-A-I-E-N-V…
PAUL: The script spy is not present.
PAUL: Alright, then just try to execute pip install hyphen r requirement.txt, let me see what happens.
PAUL: Like, there is some issue in your system. Generally, Piplet doesn't show you this output.
Naga: We've been.
PAUL: Hyphen our requirement.thg.
PAUL: Eti, you have any questions? Ehti, Jagaphati, you people can unmute yourself.
Naga: Oh, it's, saying that that script.py is not existing, yeah.
Naga: Sentin.
PAUL: This is an issue somehow. I don't know, like, you need to check your Conda installation, or you need to do a reinstallation of Conda, or you need to debug or troubleshoot. This is a system-level issue.
PAUL: You need to fix this one.
PAUL: Okay, the other way that you can work around is, just close CMD.
PAUL: Okay, the idea is you don't use conda and use that one, what you say, pure Python.
Naga: Hmm, you don't have envy?
PAUL: UV, UV or UV.
Naga: You will… no, I can install it.
PAUL: Okay, later on you can try that. For now, just try that, python-mb. Let's see what happens on that. Open a new command prompt.
Naga: Okay.
PAUL: Quanta, there is some issues.
Naga: Yeah.
Naga: Condilization.
Naga: right then.
PAUL: Go to that simple, first, go to that always folder, your simple… Yes, yes, yes, yes.
Swagatika: What's up?
PAUL: Yes.
Naga: Simple, yeah.
Swagatika: So, in Olama, all the documents we are giving this model, like, it's our private data.
Swagatika: So, if I want to connect with some online data, how can I do it, Olama?
PAUL: You can use some external type of tools.
PAUL: With Ola. Like, like, you can do a Google search, website, those type of things are possible.
Swagatika: tool calling, yes.
Swagatika: Find the answer, if I ask anything, it will combine my documents and online.
PAUL: Yes, yes, yes, yes.
Naga: Closer, hike.
PAUL: and now write Python-MVNV.
Naga: Right then.
PAUL: Yes, do the basic Python setup that I taught you in the first day of the class.
PAUL: Python hyphen MVNV.
Naga: That was my fun.
PAUL: You have to remember the commands. These are basic commands, like going forward every day.
Naga: I think it's not…
PAUL: Then Python 3 is a…
PAUL: Oh, Python is not recognized. Okay, fine, Python is not added in your environment variable, then, I think.
Naga: I can add the…
PAUL: Okay, you can test it out again.
PAUL: All right, next, Srinivas, please start sharing.
PAUL: Yes, I can see your screen, great.
PAUL: So, tell me what is the issue you are facing, and right now, ask to unmute. I have added you. Okay, please, let me know what is the issue.
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: Yeah, actually, when I am trying to do this long chain,
PAUL: Yes, have you installed the package?
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: Yeah, here only I installed.
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: We've pinched a long channel.
PAUL: hyphen ulama, not underscore ulama. Please look. Whenever I'm telling you to install something, please look into the package.
PAUL: No, it's install, no, no, no.
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: It's funny.
PAUL: Space, install, space.
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: Good evening, thank you.
PAUL: Langchen hyphen olama. After install, please give a space.
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: Yeah.
PAUL: Install give us space.
PAUL: No, no triple.
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: Sorry to sound.
PAUL: Okay, yes, now execute, now it will be working fine.
PAUL: Okay, alright, fine. Now try to do an input.
PAUL: Just copy that cell or somewhere. All imports are working.
PAUL: Ram the sale, run the sale.
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: Blue, blue, blue.
PAUL: The demo input, then run.
PAUL: Don't drive home.
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: Whoa.
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: Whoa…
PAUL: Done, done, done, done. I know, I think it should be working, there should not be any problems.
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: And I believe…
PAUL: Tell now, it's telling… okay, just try to restart the candle once.
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: Period.
PAUL: January should not happen.
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: Copied and copied.
PAUL: See that line?
PAUL: Copy that line from, yes, okay, later on, I'll be pasting it somewhere, so copy it for now.
PAUL: Okay? And, open your terminal. Open your terminal quickly.
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: It just floated in my hand.
PAUL: Okay, so right now, this is the base environment, I think you are working with .vnb, so activate the .vnb.
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: forgets me.
PAUL: Using Soul Swin? Yes.
PAUL: Soul.vin, VNV slash pin.activate.
PAUL: Because if the package is there, it should work. Bin slash activate.
PAUL: I think it should work, but again, like, I'm directly ignored.
PAUL: Yeah, hit enter. All right. Now, write Python and hit enter.
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: What else about that?
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: Whoa, whoa.
PAUL: page deadline.
PAUL: That you previously copied.
PAUL: language and olama line copy that imports document.
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: It needs, one day.
PAUL: Nothing even.
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: Been… Yeah, look at that! Get that over here! Get that out here! Get that out! Here!
PAUL: You know, paste it, it will give me a confirmation.
PAUL: Yep.
PAUL: no module, it's telling it's not there. Do an exit, exit, bracket, open, bracket, close, first brackets.
PAUL: So here, what we can do… okay, just do here then, you have used UV?
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: Yeah.
PAUL: Okay, then do an UVPIP install, langchen only.
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: Oh, I'm dead!
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: Even though I can fake you.
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: No, I have?
PAUL: Spelling of luncheon.
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: Hello?
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: Wah, wah, wah!
PAUL: Okay? And now it is done.
PAUL: Okay, so restart, restart, restart the notebook?
PAUL: Restart the kernel? No, no, no, no, no. Restart is written, no. On top, run all, beside that, restart.
PAUL: Restart. Yes, beside… little bit beside it, huh? Click on that.
PAUL: Restart the kernel.
PAUL: Okay, and execute this, sir, right now. Shift enter.
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: like, a word of God.
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: Billionaire.
PAUL: printer.
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: My God.
PAUL: Let's see.
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: It's not k-pat?
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: Top, talk.
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: Yeah, this also, I think.
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: Yeah.
PAUL: Yes, now these things will work, okay, you can test it.
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: Okay. Okay, thank you.
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: Cha, cha, cha, cha-chw.
PAUL: Next, anybody else? Jagapati is there, and Amit, let me know, because I think only you are there last, so any problems? So, Jagapati?
Amit Singh: Sir, I… yeah, I… I… I'm able to retrieve the documents.
Amit Singh: Oh…
Amit Singh: Till now, right, with Google Gemini API. I've not restarted my system, so I'll try to do Olama later in the afternoon. So, if I face challenges, you'll help me tomorrow?
PAUL: Yes, and tomorrow let me know, okay?
Amit Singh: Yeah, I mean…
PAUL: classes, I know, like, see, I feel that starting 3-4 weeks, I have to go slow.
PAUL: First few people are not coping up with my pace, that's why, so I will go slow initially, so you can let me know. Otherwise, always drop me a mail. Whenever I'm free, I can let you know that I can connect, okay? Both the ways.
Amit Singh: For OLAM, it's… I mean, after installation, it's giving this thing, a prompt, I mean, a window where… not a prompt, sorry, a window where it says new chart and settings, and it's asking to send a message and selecting a model.
PAUL: Then you can do a… that is when, like, slash wipe and do… it will be off.
Amit Singh: Slash?
PAUL: Bye.
PAUL: BYU, bye-bye.
Amit Singh: Okay.
PAUL: Eti Kumar, any questions, Eti?
PAUL: Okay, Tikumar, no questions. Jagapati?
Jagapathi: Paul, VectorDip is only used for indexing or any other purposes.
PAUL: It is used to save vectors.
Amit Singh: also started to download JEMAT3 1B model.
Amit Singh: I had selected that.
PAUL: It will take time, it will take time.
Amit Singh: Okay, okay, okay. Actually, after that, it'll…
PAUL: Yes, after that only it can run.
Amit Singh: No, by means, I thought, like, we are, I mean, asking the program to quit, basically. That's not happening.
PAUL: Show me your screen without looking into it, very hard for me to say.
Amit Singh: Wait, wait, wait.
PAUL: I'm adding you to panelists, just… Yes.
Varenya: Hey, Paul, can I share my screen?
PAUL: You are very new. I am adding to panelist.
PAUL: Jagopathy, I think he got done.
Jagapathi: Policy.
PAUL: Okay, Geropati, you were telling something just quick.
Amit Singh: I shared my screen, Paul.
PAUL: Yes. Yes. Yes, right now the model is getting downloaded.
PAUL: It's not… slash Y, we write it in the terminal, actually.
Amit Singh: I know that, I know that, I know that, yeah. So, I'll restart, and then I'll do routes.
PAUL: Okay, okay, let me know. Provide me the updates. Thank you for telling me.
Jagapathi: Yeah, so, Paul, you have a question which you're comparing with the vector DB for, like, using cosine similarity, right?
PAUL: Correct.
Jagapathi: So… What does VectorDB contain?
Jagapathi: Like, you…
PAUL: For the question vector.
Jagapathi: I don't know, so my question is, like, I have a question, which you're using embeddings, which will convert this text into the vector numbers.
Jagapathi: So, that you're comparing with the vector DP, right, again?
PAUL: Correct. The query that the end user will be asking, that query will be converted into embedding. Now, that embedding will be compared with the embeddings which are stored in our vector database.
PAUL: So for that, cosine similarity is required.
Jagapathi: So, who prepared that vector database, which you're already present in there, right? You talked in November.
PAUL: I do. You have to do, you have to create our own vector database.
Jagapathi: Okay.
Varenya: Paul, can I share my script?
PAUL: Yes, go ahead, you are in panelist.
Varenya: Yeah, clearly I just wanted to.
Varenya: Okay.
Varenya: So, initially, one question is, I just want to understand, before you were explaining this concept, right, the code you provided for lunch and to rack, for that,
Varenya: Can you explain the… draw the, one, chat, one… draw the diagram and show the… explain how the flow works? That is one thing, but I understand previously.
PAUL: Let I have done it in the last week class.
Varenya: Yeah, yeah, two classes you provided, but, if any new topics or any,
PAUL: Yes, when I discuss the theory, then I'll be talking about the flu. Right now, it's all and…
Varenya: Yeah, I understand. Today's session, when you go through each code, I understand the flow, but before starting getting into the code, just step by step, like, which star… from where it is.
PAUL: Fine, fine, fine, fine. See, it's just 2 seconds. Okay, I will just create a murmured workflow, and I will keep it there.
Varenya: Yeah, yeah, that will add more.
PAUL: I will use AI and I will do it, it is very easy for me.
Varenya: Yeah, yeah, thank you so much. I will do that. And, yeah, one question, like, the previous one of the session got hanging, so I opened new session again, and restarted, and I created the Activate the session now. So, I'm having this issue, can you help me out, like.
PAUL: For what issue? No modulum, Lancia, no Lama.
Varenya: Yeah.
PAUL: So, install Lang Channel 11. That is the solution.
Varenya: Just, I need to install it, right?
PAUL: Yes, you need to install the package, and then the imports will be fine. The same thing was happening with Srinivas.
PAUL: Okay. Told him the same stuff.
Varenya: Okay, okay, then I will try to install, and then I'll get back to you. Okay?
PAUL: Alright, yeah. If anything is there tomorrow, let me know. Tomorrow also the same.
Varenya: Yeah, sure, sure, thank you very much.
PAUL: Okay, alright, Tameth, you wanna provide the update tomorrow, fine.
PAUL: Then Naga… okay, Haga, let me know what is your status?
Naga: I'm… I don't know, I'm getting into a bad situ- this Python itself is…
Naga: not suddenly got unrecognized, and I'm installing again, and… Just going back and forth.
PAUL: Alright, provide me with an update tomorrow, okay?
PAUL: Alright…
PAUL: Fine, guys, then I'll be concluding the session, okay, tomorrow, the continuation of the notebooks that will be going on.
PAUL: Bye-bye, everyone, thanks for joining.